["Daydreamer" by Aurora playing]
Good morning. And welcome to WWDC.
早上好 欢迎参加 WWDC 全球开发者大会
WWDC is an incredibly important event to Apple, our developers and our users.
WWDC 全球开发者大会对于 Apple 我们的开发者以及用户而言极其重要
It's here that we bring some of our biggest innovations to life.
我们正是在这里实现了一些最棒的创新
And we have not stopped innovating,
我们不会停下创新的脚步
doing the work that will enrich people's lives for years to come.
我们的工作就是希望 能让人们的生活在未来更加丰富多彩
Because we're all looking forward to a more hopeful tomorrow.
因为我们都憧憬一个充满希望的明天
That's why we believe it's so important to have WWDC this year.
因此 我们认为 今年召开的 WWDC 全球开发者大会非常重要
And while it cannot possibly feel the same in here without you,
尽管各位不在现场 让这场大会的气氛与以往截然不同
I can assure you that we have a great show ahead of us.
但我向各位保证 这场大会精彩连连 值得期待
This year we're delivering the conference in a whole new way
今年 我们以全新方式召开大会
to all of you around the world, directly to your home.
无论你身处世界何地 都可直接在家中观看本次大会
And we want to welcome you to our home here at Apple Park.
我们在 Apple Park 欢迎你观看这场大会
I'd like to first talk to you about two big things
首先 我想谈论现在在全球
that are happening in the world right now.
发生的两件重要事情
To start, I want to address the topic of racism, inequality and injustice
首先 我想要谈论有关种族主义 不平等和不公正的问题
and to recognize the pain being felt throughout our nation,
我知道 举国上下都万分悲痛
especially in our Black and Brown communities,
特别是我们的黑人和棕色人种群体
after the senseless killing of George Floyd.
这是因 George Floyd 被毫无理由地杀害导致的
And while the events of this past month are sadly not new,
令人难过的是 过去这个月发生的种种事件并非首次
they have caused us to face
这让我们不得不面对
long-standing institutional inequalities and social injustices.
This country was founded on the principles of freedom and equality for all.
这个国家的建国原则是人人自由平等
For too many people and for too long, we haven't lived up to those ideals.
但在很多人眼中 这么多年来 我们都未实现这一理想
We're inspired and moved
我们十分感动 深受启发
by the passionate people around our nation and around the world
因为全国、全世界充满热忱的人们
who have stood up to demand change.
站了出来 要求改变
We must all aim far higher to build a future that lives up to our ideals.
我们必须要有更崇高的目标 才能把未来打造成符合我们理想的面貌
This means taking action.
这要求我们行动起来
Two weeks ago, we announced Apple's Racial Equity and Justice Initiative
两周前 我们发起了 Apple 的 Racial Equity and Justice Initiative
with a commitment of one hundred million dollars.
投入一亿美元
Starting in the United States, and expanding over time,
该倡议首先在美国启动 之后再逐渐推广
this initiative will challenge systemic barriers
旨在挑战制度障碍
that limit opportunity for communities of color
让有色人种群体可以在关键领域
in the critical areas of education, economic equality and criminal justice.
例如教育、经济平等和刑法司法正义中 享有更多的机会
We also announced something important for this community,
我们也宣布将为我们的群体采取重要行动
the new Developer Entrepreneur Camp for Black developers.
我们为黑人开发者创立全新的 Developer Entrepreneur Camp
We want to do everything we can to foster the brightest lights and best ideas.
我们希望尽一切努力 培养最具希望和最有创意的人才
At Apple, our mission has always been to make the world a better place,
在 Apple 我们的任务 一直是要让世界变得更好
and we're committed to being a force for change.
我们旨在成为改变世界的推动力
Right now our world is also battling a virus
现在 全球都在与病毒做抗争
that is affecting the daily lives of billions of people.
它正在影响着我们数十亿人的日常生活
We want to thank the dedicated people everywhere,
我们想要感谢为此付出努力的人们
especially our health-care workers,
特别是我们的医务工作者
who have made tremendous sacrifices to take care of those in need.
他们做出了巨大牺牲 照顾那些有需要的人
We've also seen the profound impact our products have had.
我们也注意到我们的产品 所产生的巨大影响
People are relying on them more than ever to remain connected to family and friends,
人们更加需要这些产品 从而能够与家人和朋友联系
to do their work, to express their creativity,
可以开展他们的工作 表达自己的创新想法
to be entertained as well as to entertain others.
让自己开心 同时也让他人开心
Today the world is counting on all of us,
如今 整个世界需要我们所有人团结努力
and on the products and experiences that we create, to move forward.
需要我们打造各种产品和体验来不断前行
Because throughout history,
因为在人类历史
great challenges have been met with great creativity and important breakthroughs.
伴随重大挑战而来的都是 伟大创新和重要突破
That's why we're so excited about this year's conference.
因此 我们十分期待今年的大会
This is going to be truly a unique week,
这将是非常独特新颖的一周
delivered unlike any that we've done before.
采用从未有过的开会方式
There will be more than a hundred engineering-led video sessions,
将会有一百多场工程设计的视频讲座
one-on-one consultations with Apple engineers,
和 Apple 工程师的一对一咨询
developer forums and so much more,
开发者论坛等等
delivered to you from different locations right here at Apple Park.
从 Apple Park 的不同地点推送给大家
And this year, the conference will be available
今年的大会将面对向
to our entire community of 23 million developers,
我们两千三百万的开发者群体
as well as anyone who is interested, for free.
以及感兴趣的人士免费开放
Presenting the conference in this way allows us to be more inclusive than ever.
以这种方式开会让我们更具包容性
Perhaps this will inspire the next generation of developers.
这也会激发未来一代开发者
So even though we can't be together in person,
虽然我们无法齐聚一堂
in some ways we're going to be more together than ever.
但在某种程度上 我们的联系更加紧密
Today we're going to push each of our platforms forward
今天 我们将向大家介绍我们的各个平台
in some exciting and breakthrough ways.
都将有哪些令人激动的突破性进展
With that, let's get started by sending it over to Craig.
首先从 Craig 开始
Good morning. Great to have you here.
早上好 欢迎你们参加本次大会
As you can see, we've got a lot to cover, so let's get started with iOS.
如你所见 我们有很多要谈论的内容 我们首先从 iOS 开始吧
Together with iPhone,
作为 iPhone 的系统
iOS is central to how we navigate our lives and stay connected.
iOS 对于我们的日常生活 以及与世界保持联系而言非常重要
And now we're making it even more powerful and easier to use.
现在 我们将其打造得更为强大 使用更为便捷
Our new release is iOS 14.
我们最新推出 iOS 14
This year we've spent time rethinking
今年 我们重新思考了
some of the most iconic elements of the experience on iPhone.
iPhone 体验中某些最具标志性的元素
Now it all started here,
一切从这里开始
with a carefully considered Home Screen that has truly stood the test of time.
主屏幕经过精心设计 真正经过了时间的考验
Of course, over the years, we've kept the fundamentals largely the same
当然 这么多年来 我们没有改变基本要素
but carefully added features like folders for organizing your apps,
但是精心添加了一些十分有用的新功能 例如可以整理 app 的文件夹
widgets for quick information
可以快速查询信息的小组件
and personalized experiences powered by on-device intelligence
由设备端智能技术支持的个性化体验
that serve up just the right thing at just the right moment.
这些功能都在正确的时间 起到了恰到好处的作用
It's hard to imagine iPhone without these features now.
很难想象 如果 iPhone 没有这些功能 情况会如何
Well, that brings us to this year.
让我们聚焦今年推出的新功能吧
We're doing more on our iPhones today than ever before,
我们从未像如今这样 更加依赖于 iPhone 的使用
so we've rethought some of the core elements of iOS to reflect this.
因此 我们重新设计了 iOS 的某些核心元素 让使用更为便捷
Let me give you a quick peek.
我们来一睹其风采吧
["Like This Like That" by BEGINNERS &amp; Night Panda playing]
This is gonna be amazing.
这将是非常棒的体验
Let's dig in, starting with the Home Screen.
让我们仔细看一看吧 首先，从主屏幕开始
Today's Home Screen works great, but as we get more and more apps,
现在的主屏幕体验很棒 但是当我们有越来越多的 app
we can end up with this:
就会变成这样
lots and lots of pages.
会有非常多的屏幕页面
And we tend to forget what's beyond the first couple.
除了最初的两个页面 我们会忘了在其他页面上有什么
Wouldn't it be great
如果在什么都不用做的情况下
if there were a way to organize all of those apps without doing a thing?
就可以实现 app 的整理 这不是很棒吗？
Well, this year we're doing just that with something called the App Library.
今年 我们采用 App 资源库 实现了这一功能
It's a new space at the end of your Home Screen pages
这是在主屏幕所有页面之后 所创建的一个新空间
that automatically organizes all your apps
它会自动整理你的 app
in one simple and easy-to-navigate view.
以简约和便捷的方式供你浏览
Let me show you.
让我来展示一下
Here's my Home Screen.
这是我的主屏幕
Now, like you, I have muscle memory built for the first page or two,
我现在和你一样 很清楚前两页中有什么
but when it comes to all of these pages,
但关于其他页面上的很多东西
well, honestly, I've lost track of where a lot of things are.
说实话 我就不记得它们的位置了
And that's where the App Library comes in.
此时便是 App 资源库大展身手的时候了
You can see that all of my apps are automatically organized here.
你可以看到我所有的 app 在这里经过自动整理
In fact, now with the App Library,
实际上 通过使用 App 资源库
I actually don't need all those pages for all my apps.
我不需要让我所有的 app 占据那么多屏幕页面
So we created an easy way to hide app pages.
因此 我们打造了一种便捷方式 来隐藏 app 页面
I just go into jiggle mode, tap the dots at the bottom,
我进入摇动模式 轻点底部的翻页提示圆点
and check this out,
请看
I get a zoomed-out view of all my app pages.
现在显示的是所有 app 页面的缩放视图
I can simply tap to hide the pages I no longer need.
我只需轻点来隐藏不再需要的页面
Just like that.
就像这样
And now with those pages hidden,
现在 这些页面已被隐藏
App Library is always just a swipe or two away.
只需轻轻扫屏幕一两下 就可以进入 App 资源库了
So here in App Library, getting to the app I'm looking for is really easy.
在 App 资源库中 找到所需的 app 真的非常简单
Up at the top I have the Search field,
在顶部有搜索栏
and I get all my apps organized from A to Z.
我的所有 app 都是按字母 A 到 Z 排序的
Now over here on the upper left I have Suggestions.
在左上角 我有建议 App
It uses on-device intelligence
它采用设备端智能技术
to show me the apps that I'm likely to need next.
来显示我可能接下来需要使用的 app
And on the right is Recently Added,
在右上方 则是最近添加的 app
giving me access to the apps that I've recently downloaded from the App Store.
可以让我使用 最近从 App Store 下载的 app
And below are intelligently curated categories.
下方是经过智能分类的 app
So I can tap into a category like Apple Arcade
我可以轻点进入一个分类 例如 Apple Arcade
and see all of my apps in that category.
并且查看这个分类中我所有的 app
Now let's go back.
现在返回上一步
You may notice that in each of these categories
你可能注意到 在所有这些分类中
the apps I use most are right here at the top level,
我最常使用的 app 都在最顶端
so I can launch one of these directly with just a tap.
因此 我只需轻点一下 便可直接启动其中一个 app
So that's App Library.
这就是 App 资源库
We think this is gonna make it easier than ever to get to your apps.
我们认为这会让你 比以往更加方便地找到 app
Next, let's turn to Widgets.
接下来 我们来看一看小组件
Today, widgets help you get information at a glance.
现在的小组件可以让你速览信息
But a lot has changed since we first introduced these.
但从我们最初引入小组件时 到现在已经有了很多变化
Now we have Apple Watch, where we're able to surface so much information
现在我们有 Apple Watch 可以通过戴在手腕上的小屏幕
on a small screen that you wear on your wrist.
就能够浏览很多信息
Well, this year, we're taking all that we've learned
今年 我们根据所有以往经验
to create a completely reimagined experience for widgets.
专心针对小组件进行了重新设计
To start, they're more beautiful and data rich.
首先 它们更为美观 信息更为丰富
And we're introducing different sizes,
同时我们还添加了不同的尺寸
so you can choose one that best fits your needs.
因此 你可以选择自己所需的尺寸
Let's take a look at them in iOS 14.
让我们看看它们在 iOS 14 中的表现吧
So let's swipe over to Today View and take a look at our new widgets.
让我们轻扫到“今天”视图 查看我们新的小组件
They're just beautiful.
它们十分美观
And the new designs are more data rich than ever.
新设计让数据比以往更加丰富
And you can see they now come in a variety of sizes.
你可以看到 它们有各种不同的尺寸
So you can pick just the right level of information for each one.
你只需要为每个小组件选择合适的信息量
Now we like these new widgets so much,
我们太喜欢这些小组件了
we wanted to make them even more accessible.
希望能更加容易地触达它们
So check this out.
请看
I'm just gonna tap and hold on the Weather widget,
我要轻点并按住天气小组件
and I can drag it out of Today View and onto my Home Screen.
然后我可以将其从“今天”视图中 拖动出来至主屏幕
And watch, as I move it around,
请看 当我将它来回移动时
the apps just dance out of the way to make space for my new widget.
app 会跳到其他地方 为新的小组件让位
Let's add a second one.
让我们再添加一个
Just gonna tap the plus here in the upper left
轻点左上角的“+”键
and grab on to Podcasts.
抓住播客小组件
I can drop it just like that.
我可以像这样放下
Now I'm gonna swipe over to page 2 here and bring back up the Widget Gallery.
现在我要轻扫到第 2 页 回到小组件图廊
The gallery is a great place to explore widgets.
图廊是探索小组件的好地方
Now when I tap on one,
现在当我轻点一个时
I can actually page through all of the different sizes available.
我能浏览可用的不同尺寸
Just like this.
就像这样
But, you know, right now what I want to do is grab this widget up top.
但是 你知道 我现在想把这个小组件放到顶部
It's a really special one. It's called the Smart Stack.
这个小组件真的很特殊 它被称之为智能叠放
Just gonna tap it and drop it here.
只需轻点 然后放在这里
With the Smart Stack, I can easily swipe through widgets
通过智能叠放 我可以轻扫不同的小组件
to pick just the one I want for the moment.
选择我此时需要的小组件
But what's really cool
但真正很酷的事情是
is that the Smart Stack can actually do this for me automatically.
智能叠放实际上可以自动实现这一功能
So in the morning, I can get my news briefing.
因此在清晨 它会给我显示新闻简报
Throughout the day, find out when I have a meeting coming up.
在白天 它会告知我何时开会
And in the evening, I might get a summary of my activity for the day.
在晚上 它会显示 我这一天的健身记录摘要
So that's widgets on the Home Screen.
这就是主屏幕上的小组件
We're excited to see how everyone will customize them in their own way.
我们很期待看到 大家如何自定义使用这些小组件
Next, we're also bringing Picture in Picture to iPhone.
其次 我们还为 iPhone 增加了画中画功能
So you can access apps on your iPhone
因此 在你观看视频
while watching video or talking on a FaceTime call.
或者 FaceTime 通话时 可以使用 iPhone 上的 app
Let me show you.
我来展示一下
So here on my Home Screen,
在我的主屏幕上
the Smart Stack is showing me the TV widget.
智能叠放正显示我的 TV 小组件
So I can just tap to start playing a show.
所以我可以轻点它 开始播放一个节目
Now check this out. When I swipe to go Home,
现在请看 当我轻扫回到主屏幕时
the video automatically goes into Picture in Picture
视频自动变成画中画模式
right over the Home Screen.
停留在主屏幕上方
And when I launch another app, like Notes, I can keep watching.
当我启动另一个 app 例如备忘录 我可以继续看视频
Now I can drag the picture to another part of the screen.
我可以把该视频拖移到屏幕的另一个地方
If I want to make it bigger, I can even pinch to zoom.
如果愿意 我甚至可以使用双指放大该视频
And as I move between applications it stays with me.
如果我在 app 之间来回切换 它也会一直在主屏幕上
And what's cool is I can also swipe it to the side,
很酷的一点是 我也可以把它轻扫到一侧
and the audio keeps playing when it's off-screen.
即使在屏幕之外 音频仍继续播放
Now here on the Home Screen I can bring it back out if I want.
在主屏幕上 我可以随时把它拖回来
And I have controls to get back to full-screen playback,
我能够让它全屏播放
or I can just tap the "X" to close it.
或者轻点“X”键将其关闭
And that's Picture in Picture video.
这就是画中画视频
It's a great way to continue enjoying your video
当利用iPhone 来做其他一切事情时候
while tapping into everything else your iPhone can do for you.
你可以继续观看视频 这真的很棒
And that's a quick look at the updates to the core elements of iOS.
这就是 iOS 核心元素的更新概览
We think these new features are gonna make iOS even more helpful in the moment.
我们认为这些新功能会让 iOS 更加有用
Another iconic experience that's getting a major update is Siri.
另一个得到重大更新的标志性功能 就是 Siri
As much as Siri has advanced over the years,
多年来 虽然 Siri 不断更新改进
the visual interface for interacting with it has remained largely unchanged.
但是与 Siri 互动的 交互界面基本上没有改变
When you use Siri, your iPhone switches to this full-screen UI,
当你使用 Siri 时 你的 iPhone 会切换至全屏交互界面
obscuring your current context.
遮挡其他所有信息
So this year, we've completely redesigned the Siri experience
因此在今年 我们完全重新设计了 Siri 体验
with a new compact design.
采用了全新紧凑的设计方式
It makes tasks like launching apps incredibly seamless.
让启动 app 等这样的任务做到无缝接合
For example, if you say, "Open Safari,"
例如你说：“打开 Safari 浏览器”
Siri pops up at the bottom of the screen and instantly launches the app.
Siri 会从屏幕底部弹出 立刻打开这个 app
Or if you ask for information, like the weather,
或者如果你要查询信息 比如天气
results appear at the top of the screen just like a notification.
查询结果会像通知一样出现在屏幕顶端
Now this is especially great
特别是当你需要
when there's information you want to reference on-screen.
查看屏幕上的信息时 这一功能就真的是太方便了
For example, you could ask Siri to add to your grocery list.
例如 你可以让 Siri 添加你的购物清单
So that's the new Siri design in iOS 14.
这就是 iOS 14 中 Siri 的新设计
But the UI is only part of the story.
但用户交互界面仅仅是 此次更新的一部分内容
To tell you more about how we're making Siri smarter than ever,
如果你想知道 我们如何让 Siri 变得比以往都要聪明
I'll hand it off to Yael Garten.
那就有请 Yael Garten 为我们介绍吧
Thanks, Craig.
Siri's getting smarter and even more helpful every day,
and I'm really excited to share the latest updates with you.
我很高兴与大家分享最新的更新
Siri helps you in a ton of little ways every day:
Siri 每天无微不至地为大家提供帮助
playing the morning news, ordering a coffee, getting directions,
播放早间新闻、订购咖啡、导航
setting the alarm before going to bed and so much more.
睡前设置闹铃等等
In fact, Siri's helping so many of you
事实上 Siri 为许多人提供了帮助
with a staggering 25 billion requests each month.
其每月的请求使用量高达二百五十亿次
And Siri's getting more helpful every day.
Siri 变得越来越有用
Siri's always been great for getting information
Siri 向来都是获取信息的绝佳方式
and now has over 20 times more facts than just three years ago.
其目前掌握的信息为三年前的 20 多倍
For more complex questions
对于更复杂的问题
like "How do hybrid cars work?" or "What causes seasons?",
如“混合动力汽车的工作原理” 或“季节如何产生”
we recently introduced answers from websites across the Internet,
我们最近从互联网引入了答案
enabling Siri to help you find even more answers.
从而使 Siri 能帮你找到更多答案
Another way Siri helps is with communication, like sending messages.
Siri 的另一个功能为通信 如发送消息
This year, you can now ask Siri to send an audio message,
Siri 从今年开始支持发送音频消息
and Siri will start recording.
Siri 将会录音
This is great when you really want to have the emotion of your voice come through.
如果你想用声音传递情感 这是一个很棒的功能
Another popular way to send messages with your voice is using dictation.
另一种比较流行的方式为 通过听写来用语音发送消息
Keyboard Dictation uses the same speech recognition as Siri.
键盘启动的听写功能使用了与 Siri 相同的语音识别技术
And leveraging the power of the Neural Engine,
并利用了神经网络引擎技术
we are now able to run dictation on-device.
我们现在能够在设备端运行听写
This provides great accuracy and privacy.
这可以实现很高的准确性与私密性
When communicating with someone in another language, Siri can help with translations.
当你用其他语言跟别人交流时 Siri 可帮忙翻译
This year we're expanding to support many new language pairs.
今年我们扩大了对许多新语种的支持
This is hugely popular,
这非常受欢迎
but we know our users want more than just translating phrases.
但我们知道 用户想要的 不仅仅是翻译短语
They want to have entire conversations.
他们希望能翻译完整对话
And we believe conversations between languages
我们认为多语言之间的对话
should feel natural and easy and have the ability to stay private.
应自然轻松并能够保持私密性
That's why we're introducing a new app called Translate.
为此我们引入了名为翻译的新 app
It is designed to be the best and easiest-to-use app for conversations.
该 app 旨在成为 最出色且最易用的对话 app
And it can work completely off-line, keeping your conversations private.
它可以完全离线运行 保持对话的私密性
Using advanced on-device machine learning and the powerful Neural Engine,
借助设备端机器学习技术 和强大的神经网络引擎技术
you can translate your text and voice
你可以翻译文本和语音
between any combination of these 11 languages.
此功能支持 11 种语言的任意组合
So I could have a conversation with someone in Mandarin,
所以我能与讲中文的人对话
and they could have a conversation with someone in Russian.
他们能与讲俄语的人对话
Just tap on the microphone and say, "What are your store hours?"
只需轻点麦克风并说出 “你的营业时间为几点？”
[Siri reads Spanish translation]
[Yael] You get back the text and audio right away.
你便可以立马获得语音和文本
And just turn the phone to landscape to open conversation mode.
只需将手机调至横屏 以打开对话模式
We've designed a side-by-side view
我们设计了并排视图
that's easy for two people to know which side to follow in the conversation.
两个人可轻松了解 在对话中应跟进屏幕的哪一区域
This mode is incredibly intuitive, with just a single microphone button
该模式非常直观 只需一个麦克风按钮
because the app intelligently detects the language spoken
因为 app 可智能检测所说的语言
and shows translation on the correct side of the screen.
并在屏幕的正确区域显示翻译
Translate will make communicating between languages easier than ever before,
翻译使各语言之间的沟通比以往更方便
connecting people in new ways.
并为人们提供了新的沟通方式
And we can't wait for you to try it.
我们迫不及待地等你试试
Thanks, Yael.
谢谢你 Yael
Next up, Messages.
接下来是信息
Messages is how many of us communicate with people most important to us.
信息是我们大部分人与对我们 最重要的人进行沟通的一种方式
And now we're using it more than ever.
现在我们对它的使用比以往更多
Compared to just a year ago,
仅与一年前相比
we have a record number of users sending a record number of messages.
And we've seen people use Messages more and more
我们发现越来越多的人在使用信息
to keep in touch with their closest groups.
This year, we're introducing
我们今年将引入
a new way to stay connected with your most important conversations,
可使你在最重要的 对话中保持连接的新方法
giving you new ways to express your identity with Memoji
通过拟我表情为你 提供表示个性的新方法
and making big changes to how we communicate in groups.
并对在群组中的沟通方式作出大改变
To tell you more, here's Stacey Lysik.
下面有请 Stacey Lysik 来进一步讲解
Thanks, Craig.
First, let's get started with Conversations.
From the beginning, Messages was designed
信息的设计初衷
to make it really easy to get to your newest messages.
是为了让大家能够 十分轻松地获取最新信息
But with so many active conversations,
但由于存在大量的活跃对话
sometimes it can be tough to get to the ones that are most important to you.
有时很难找到对你最重要的人
So we are introducing a new way
所以我们引入了
to let you stay connected to your most important conversations:
使你能与最重要的对话保持连接的新方法
by letting you pin them at the top of your list
通过在列表顶部置顶来实现
so you can always get to them.
从而使你总能找到他们
And you can see messages as they come in with a beautiful animation on the pin.
置顶的联络人发送信息时 会以美丽动画来呈现
Next, let's talk about expressing yourself with Memoji.
接下来我们来讲一讲 如何通过拟我表情来表达自我
There are over one trillion ways to customize your identity with Memoji.
借助拟我表情可通过超过 一万亿种方式来定制您的个性
In iOS 14, we're adding even more ways to create your look
我们在 iOS 14 中加入了 用于打造你的外观的更多方式
with over 20 new hair and headwear styles
其中包括 20 多种新发型和头饰
to let you reflect your hobby, profession and personality.
以反映你的爱好、职业与个性
We've also added something that's even more relevant today: face coverings.
我们也加入了与当前更贴合的功能：口罩
And we're adding more age options too.
我们还加入了更多年龄选项
My favorite way of using Memoji is with Memoji stickers.
我最喜爱的拟我表情使用方式 是使用拟我表情贴纸
And now we have three brand-new Memoji stickers
我们现在拥有三种全新的拟我表情贴纸
that let you send a hug, a fist bump or even a blush to your friends.
这使你能够向朋友发送 拥抱、碰拳或甚至是害羞表情
Last, let's chat about groups.
最后 我们来谈论一下群组
When you're talking to a group, sometimes there's so much going on,
提到群组 有时会太过活跃
it can be hard to keep track of the conversation.
可能很难追踪对话
So this year, we're gonna help you bring order to the chaos.
因此我们今年将帮助你化混乱为秩序
First we're adding inline replies
首先我们将加入精准回复
that let you reply directly to a specific message.
以使你能够直接回复特定信息
You can view replies in the full conversation
你可以在完整的会话中查看回复
or you can view them as their own thread so you can focus in on the specific topic.
你还可以只查看特定的对话往来 这样就可以侧重于特定主题
To make it even more clear who a message was meant for,
为更明确信息是发送给谁的
we're introducing mentions.
我们推出了提到
With mentions, you can just type someone's name
借助提到 你只需键入某人的名字
to direct a message to them.
便可向其发送信息
And now you have the ability to only be notified
现在你能够设置仅在群组对话中
when you're mentioned in the group conversation.
被提到时才会收到提醒
And check out the top of this conversation.
看一看这个对话的顶部
We have an all-new design for how groups appear.
我们全新设计了群组的呈现方式
It lets you see all the members of your group,
这使你可以查看组中的所有成员
where the most recently active people are shown largest.
And, for the first time ever,
你有史以来第一次
you can create a unique visual identity for your group
可以通过创建群组照片 来为群组打造
by setting a group photo
独特的视觉形象
or customizing your group's look with an emoji.
或通过表情符号来定义群组外观
Inside the conversation
在对话中
you see group members' photos around the image.
你会看到围绕图像的组成员照片
Of course it looks great as a pin.
被置顶的头像当然好看啦
You know who's most recently commented in the group
你知道谁最近在群组中发表了评论
because their photo will appear around the outside of the pin.
因为他们的照片将围绕 置顶标记的外部呈现
And that's what's coming to Messages in iOS 14:
这就是在 iOS 14 中加入信息的新功能
all-new pinned conversations, fun updates to Memoji
全新的置顶对话 有趣的拟我表情更新
and powerful improvements to groups.
以及强大的群组功能改进
Thanks, Stacey.
谢谢你 Stacey
Next, let's take a look at features that help us while we're out and about.
接下来我们来看一下 外出活动时对我们有帮助的功能
Now we know that life looks very different for many of us right now,
我们知道 现在我们大多数人的生活都变了样
but it won't always be this way.
但情况不会一直是这样
And as things start to open up,
等一切都开始好转之后
we have a new set of features that will help us explore the world again,
我们加入了一组新功能 可以帮助你再次探索这个世界
starting with Maps.
就从地图开始
Apple Maps is the best way to navigate and explore the world,
Apple 地图是导航和探索世界的极佳方式
all while protecting your privacy.
同时也能保护你的隐私
Over the past several years, we've added many great features,
在过去几年里 我们加入了许多很棒的功能
and of course we've been rebuilding our map from the ground up.
当然 我们彻底重新构建了地图
Our new map finished rolling out across the US earlier this year
我们的新地图已于 今年早些时候在美国推出
and brought with it better navigation and far richer detail
新地图具有更出色的导航以及更丰富的
for roads, pedestrian paths, landcover and more.
道路、步道、地貌等细节
The new map also offers more accurate information for places
新地图也提供更精确的位置信息
and allows us to build incredible features like Look Around.
并使我们能够构建诸如 四处看看等不可思议的功能
Maps has come a long way, and people have noticed.
地图一路走来取得了很大的进展 人们注意到了这一点
Just look at this quote from Fast Company.
来引用一下 Fast Company 说过的这段话吧
"Apple Maps has improved by leaps and bounds
“Apple 地图已大幅改进
and is a formidable rival to Google Maps.
它已成为 Google 地图的强大竞争对手
It's also arguably got the better UI,
有人说它还有更出色的用户交互界面
and by far-- by far-- the better privacy policy."
但它的隐私政策绝对遥遥领先”
We're excited to announce
we're bringing our new map to more countries later this year,
我们将在今年晚些时候 将新地图推广到更多国家和地区
including the UK, Ireland and Canada.
包括英国、爱尔兰和加拿大
In addition to the rich detail and improved accuracy,
除了丰富的细节和更高的精度以外
the new map serves as the foundation for many great new features.
In iOS 14, we're adding things
我们在 iOS 14 中加入了一些新功能
that will make it easier for people to find places they love
使人们能更轻松地找到他们喜爱的地方
and help them get to where they're going
并帮助他们以更环保的方式
in ways that are better for the environment.
抵达目的地
To tell you more, I'll hand it off to Meg Frost.
下面有请 Meg Frost 来为大家提供更多信息
Thanks, Craig.
First, let's talk about finding great places.
We have millions of people coming to Maps every day
数百万人每天通过地图
to discover great new places,
来探索很棒的新地方
whether they're planning their next big vacation
他们可能是为了规划下一个假期
or just looking for something to eat nearby.
或者只是为了去寻找附近的餐馆
In iOS 14,
在 iOS 14 中
the Maps team will be working with some of the world's most trusted brands
地图团队将与全球一些 最值得信赖的品牌合作
to offer amazing Guides.
以提供出色的指南
Guides for great places to eat, shop,
介绍吃喝玩乐和购物的好去处
meet friends or explore in cities around the world.
以及朋友聚会或探索世界各地的城市
You can save Guides so you can easily get back to them later,
在保存指南后 你可以在以后轻松地调用
and the best part is they automatically update when new places are added,
最棒的是 在添加 新位置后它们会自动更新
so you always have the latest recommendations.
因此你始终可以获得最新的推荐
In addition to helping you discover great new places,
除了帮助你探索很棒的新地方以外
Maps helps you get there in a way that's better for the planet.
地图可帮助你 以对地球更环保的方式前往那里
For years, Maps has made it easy to navigate
这些年来 地图使人们能够
using environmentally-friendly options like public transit and walking.
轻松地以环保的方式导航 如搭乘公共交通工具和步行
With iOS 14, we're introducing great new features
在 iOS 14 中 我们引进了很棒的新功能
to help our users reduce their carbon footprint,
以帮助我们的用户降低碳排放
and our first one is also our most requested:
第一个 也是呼声最高的功能
It's Cycling.
骑行
We've built an incredible cycling experience
我们打造了出色的骑行体验
that helps you get around town on your bike.
这可以帮助你骑自行车在城市穿行
We're adding a dedicated cycling option to Maps
我们将专用的骑行选项加入到了地图中
which allows users to ride their bike along bike lanes, paths and roads.
这使用户能够沿自行车道 小径和道路来骑行
Maps takes elevation into account
地图考虑到了海拔高度
to let you know if you're in for a challenging uphill workout
这使你了解自己是否正在 进行有挑战的爬坡体能训练
or a leisurely flat ride.
或在进行舒适的平地骑行
You can also see if your route includes quiet or busy roads.
你还可以查看路径 是否包含安静或繁忙的道路
We'll even let you know if you have a steep passage coming up
我们甚至还能让你知道 是否即将遇到陡峭的道路
or if you'll need to carry your bike up the stairs.
或者是否需要扛着自行车上楼梯
You can also choose to avoid stairs altogether.
你也可以选择完全避免楼梯
With iOS 14, we're bringing cycling to New York City, LA,
在 iOS 14 中 我们向纽约、洛杉矶
the San Francisco Bay Area,
旧金山湾区
along with a number of cities in China like Shanghai and Beijing.
以及诸如上海和北京等 中国城市开放了骑行功能
And we'll be adding many more cities in the coming months.
我们将在未来几个月里加入更多城市
For environmentally conscious drivers, we're also introducing EV routing.
对于有环保意识的驾驶员 我们还推出了电动汽车路线规划
If you have an electric car,
如果你拥有电动汽车
Maps is going to help eliminate range anxiety.
地图将有助于消除里程焦虑
With iOS 14, Maps will track your current charge
iOS 14 的地图将追踪你当前的电量
and factor in things like elevation and weather
并计算爬坡高度和天气等因素
to automatically add charging stops along your route.
以便沿你的路径自动导航去充电站
And Maps will know which type of charger works for your car,
地图将了解哪类充电站适合你的汽车
making sure to only route you to compatible stations.
以确保将你导航至兼容的充电站
We're working with a number of manufacturers
我们正与许多制造商合作
to support EV routing in their vehicles,
以便支持其电动汽车的路线规划
including BMW and Ford,
这包括 BMW 和 Ford
and we'll be adding many more in the near future.
我们在不久的将来 将加入对更多品牌的支持
Cities around the world are also working to improve air quality and reduce traffic,
全球的城市也在致力于 改善空气质量和减轻交通拥堵
so we're adding congestion and green zones to Maps
所以我们在地图中加入了拥堵区和通畅区
to easily see where they are along with alternate routing options.
让用户能够轻松查看 其所在位置以及替代路线选项
In addition, drivers in China
此外 中国的驾驶员
can securely store their license plate number on their iPhone,
可安全地将其车牌号存储在 iPhone 中
and Maps will let them know which days they can enter congested city centers
地图将能够让他们知道 哪些日子可以进入拥挤的市中心
based on that number.
车牌号是否限号
And those are just some of the great new features
这些只是即将在 iOS 14 的 Apple 地图中
coming to Apple Maps in iOS 14,
推出的一些新功能
making Maps the best product
从而使地图成为了最出色的产品
to help users explore and navigate their world.
可以帮助用户在他们的世界各地探索导航
Thanks, Meg.
谢谢你 Meg
And now, on to CarPlay,
现在介绍 CarPlay
which has transformed the driving experience for iPhone owners
该应用改变了 iPhone 用户的驾驶体验
by being the smarter, safer way to use the apps you love in your car.
CarPlay is everywhere, and it's incredibly popular.
Here in the US, it's available on basically every new car.
在美国 几乎每一辆新车均支持该功能
And worldwide, it's available on over 80% of new cars sold
在全球 该功能可用于 超过 80% 的新售出汽车
and has quickly become the default in-car experience for so many people.
并快速成为许多用户的默认车内体验
People love CarPlay, and we get some really passionate reactions.
Joanna Stern says it makes her life "infinitely better."
We have some great updates for iOS 14.
我们在 iOS 14 中加入了一些很棒的更新
First up, we have new wallpaper options perfect for the car.
首先 我们新增了 非常适合汽车的新壁纸选项
And we're adding support for new categories of CarPlay apps:
我们加入了对 CarPlay app 的新类别的支持
parking, EV charging and quick food ordering.
停车、电动汽车充电和快速点餐
In addition to this, we're really excited for the next step
除此之外 我们对转型的下一步 感到非常兴奋
in how we're transforming your relationship with your car
即通过重新思考车钥匙来转变
by rethinking car keys.
你与汽车的关系
They've been around for over a hundred years,
车钥匙已存在了一百多年
but they've become big, bulky and ripe for reimagining.
但它们正变得又大又笨重 重新思考的时机已到
To tell you more about what we have planned,
为了让你进一步了解我们的计划
let's go to the garage with Emily Schubert.
我们现在去车库 让 Emily Schubert 来聊一聊
Thanks, Craig.
I'm excited to introduce a digital version of car keys.
Now you can leave your keys at home
and unlock and start your car with your iPhone.
通过 iPhone 即可解锁和启动你的汽车
And the very first car to support this will be the new 2021 BMW 5 Series.
支持这一功能的首款汽车 为新的 2021 年款 BMW 5 系
Let me show you how it works.
我来介绍一下其工作原理
It's super simple.
这超级简单
-It uses NFC, and you just tap to unlock. -[beeps]
它使用了 NFC 只需轻点即可解锁
And I place my phone on the charging pad and then push to start.
我将手机放在充电板上 然后按下以启动
[chimes]
But this goes beyond just one less thing you have to keep in your pocket.
但这不仅仅是让你的 口袋里少放了一件东西
Digital keys have security benefits.
数码钥匙具有安全优势
They live in the Secure Element of your iPhone,
它们基于你的 iPhone 的安全元件
and if it goes missing, you can turn off your keys remotely via iCloud.
如果手机丢失 你可以通过 iCloud 远程关闭你的钥匙
They're even easier to share than a physical key.
它们甚至比物理钥匙更易于分享
Copies don't involve trips to the dealership.
无需去经销商门店复制钥匙
And you can share from wherever you are with iMessage.
你可以在任何地方 通过 iMessage 来分享钥匙
Let's give Craig a key so he can drive home after we're done here.
让我们给 Craig 一把钥匙 这样他就可以在我们介绍完后开车回家
With each key you share, you can set options,
对于你分享的每把钥匙 你可以设置选项
like a restricted driving profile, perfect for teen drivers.
就像是限制驾驶的参数配置文件 这非常适合青少年司机
Which is tempting,
虽然我很想这么做
but we'll give Craig full access.
但我们还是给 Craig 提供全部驾驶权限吧
[phone chimes]
-[phone chimes] -Full access? Thanks, Emily.
The new BMW will be available to customers next month.
新款 BMW 将于下个月向客户推出
In addition to adding this feature to iOS 14,
除了将这一功能加入到 iOS 14 以外
we're also enabling it in iOS 13,
我们也将在 iOS 13 中启用此功能
so customers can use their car keys even sooner.
Of course, we want this to work in any car,
so we've been working on standards with industry groups.
所以我们致力于与行业团体一起制定标准
And this is just the beginning.
这只是一个开始
We're working on technology that will leverage our U1 chip,
我们正在开发技术 这将利用到我们的 U1 芯片
which uses Ultra Wideband technology for precise spatial awareness.
它将利用超宽频技术 来实现精确的空间感知
So you'll be able to leave your iPhone in your bag or pocket
所以即使将 iPhone 放在包或口袋中
and still securely unlock and start your car.
也能够安全地解锁和启动汽车
We expect to see support for this standard starting in new cars next year.
我们有望在来年的汽车中 看到对于这一标准功能的支持
Now, let's turn to the App Store.
现在 我们前往 App Store
Twelve years ago,
12 年前
we revolutionized the industry with the launch of the App Store.
我们通过推出 App Store 彻底改变了行业
Today we have so many amazing apps that offer a rich set of experiences,
目前 我们有许多出色的功能 可为你提供一套丰富的体验
we can truly say that for everything we want to do,
我们可以肯定地说 不管你想做什么
"There's an app for that."
“总有一款 app 能帮到你”
So now it's time for us to extend the success of the App Store
现在是时候延伸 App Store 的成功
and make apps available and accessible in whole new ways.
并使用户能以 全新的方式拥有和使用 app
What if you could have the right app you needed at just the right moment?
如果你在某个时刻能获得你所需要的 app 那会怎么样？
Let's look at what it would be like if you did.
我们来看看如果真能这样 会是什么情况
[narrator] Today, no matter what you want to do,
there's an app for that.
But what if you don't have the app you need right when you need it?
Like when you need to pay for parking. Well, now there's an App Clip for that.
[car chirps]
Ooh. Look, a new coffee shop.
There's an App Clip for that.
Or a friend sends you a message with a print you like.
That looks nice.
那看起来真好看
Looking for somewhere to eat nearby? App Clip.
Very health conscious of you.
Hey, there's a scooter. Let's take it for a spin.
看 有辆电动滑板车 我们骑上去兜风吧
Yep. App Clip.
没错，用 App Clip 就对了
Mmm. Ice cream. Wait. There isn't one for that yet?
Well, soon there could be an App Clip for that.
很快它就会有属于自己的 App Clip 了
And that.
还有这个
-And that. -[martial artist] Hi-yah!
An App Clip is a small part of an app.
App Clip 是 app 的一小部分
It's light and fast and easy to discover,
它轻便快捷 易于发现
so you can quickly get what you need right when you need it.
可以让你快速得到你想要的东西
Everything about App Clips is designed for speed.
App Clips 的一切都是为速度而设计的
They start with this card which quickly pops up.
首先是这张快速弹出的卡
And with just a tap, you can launch the App Clip.
只要轻点一下 你就能启动 App Clip
You don't need to enter credit card numbers
你无需输入信用卡号码
because App Clips can use Apple Pay for payments.
因为 App Clips 支持使用 Apple Pay 付款
And you don't have to manually log into an account
你也不需要手动登录账号
because it can take advantage of Sign in with Apple.
因为它支持通过 Apple 登录
App Clips won't clutter your Home Screen
App Clips 不会挤满你的主界面
and will only stay along as long as you need them.
它只会在你需要用到它时出现
But you can easily launch recently used App Clips from the new App Library.
但你可以在全新的 App 资源库里 轻松找到最近使用过的 App Clips
It's always easy to download the full app,
下载完整版的 app 总是容易的
and this makes App Clips an easy way to discover
而这也让 App Clips 成了
more of what the App Store has to offer.
探索 App Store 的简易方法
And discovery is key.
而“探索”就是关键
App Clips are all about getting to a part of an app at the moment you need it,
App Clips 让你在需要用到某款 app 时 可以获得它的一部分功能
so it was critical that we made them really easy to find.
App Clips can be easily discovered and launched from the web.
你可以在浏览器里 轻松探索和启动 App Clips
You can launch App Clips from Messages when friends share them with you.
当朋友给你分享信息时 你可以在信息里启动 App Clips
When you want to order takeout from a restaurant in Maps,
当你想在地图里点外卖时
you can launch an App Clip right from a place card.
你可以直接从地点信息卡里 启动 App Clips
You'll be able to tap on NFC tags out in the world, on things like parking meters.
你可以在现实世界中的物品 比如停车计费器上 轻触 NFC 标签
Or you can scan QR codes
或者你可以扫描
to launch App Clips that work with products you purchase.
所购物品上的二维码来启动 App Clips
The best way to discover App Clips will be with the new Apple-designed App Clip code.
探索 App Clips 最好的方式就是通过 Apple 新设计的 App Clips 码
So when you see one, you'll know that there's an App Clip waiting for you.
当你看到它时 你就知道有款 App Clip 在等着你了
They incorporate both a visual code and NFC,
它们结合了视觉编码和 NFC
so you tap on them or scan them with the camera to bring up an App Clip.
所以你可以轻点 或用相机扫描以启动 App Clip
App Clips will be great for businesses that already have apps.
App Clips 非常适合 已经拥有 app 的企业
But we want to be able to use App Clips everywhere,
但我们想随时随地使用 App Clips
including smaller spots that may not have their own app.
包括在尚未拥有 app 的小型商家
So we made it possible for apps like Yelp, which support multiple businesses,
所以我们可以让 Yelp 这种支持多商家的 app
to create App Clip experiences for each of the places they work with.
为每个与他们合作的地方 创建 App Clip 体验
Developers will create App Clips from a part of an app,
开发人员会使用 Xcode 和 SDK 的全部性能
using Xcode and the full power of the SDK.
来从 app 的一部分创建 App Clips
To ensure that they launch quickly,
为保证它们能够快速启动
they'll need to be less than 10 megabytes in size.
它们的大小必须小于10MB
And that's App Clips.
这就是 App Clips
Immediately discoverable,
支持即刻被发现
small in size, so they launch fast,
体积小巧以便能够快速启动
integrated Apple Pay for easy payment,
融入 Apple Pay 以实现轻松付款
Sign in with Apple for quick and privacy-friendly login
通过 Apple 登录 实现快速且私密的登录体验
and the option to download the full app from the App Store
你还可以选择 从 App Store 上下载完整版 app
when you want to keep it around.
以便长期保留
We can't wait to see all the App Clips developers will create.
我们等不及要看 开发人员创建出来的各种 App Clips 了
And that's iOS 14.
这就是 iOS 14
It's a huge release that transforms the core experience of iPhone,
它是会改变 iPhone 核心体验的 一个重大版本
with redesigned widgets right on the Home Screen
主屏幕上有着重新设计的小组件
and a new way to organize your apps with the App Library.
还有全新的 App 资源库帮助你整理 app
It adds incredible updates to some of the most popular apps,
它给一些最受欢迎的 app 进行了很棒的升级
with powerful improvements to Messages and Maps,
对信息和地图做出了重大改进
and introduces a whole new way to tap into apps
而且推出了使用 app 的全新方式
with App Clips.
也就是 App Clips
And next up, iPadOS.
接下来要介绍的是 iPadOS
["S.S. Luker's Mom" by Oh Sees playing]
Oh, hey, we made it.
嘿 我们赶上了
All right. Well, let's jump right in.
好了 我们开始吧
iPadOS builds on all the amazing features of iOS
iPadOS 建立在 iOS 强大的性能之上
while adding unique capabilities
同时加入了一些独特功能
that deliver a distinct experience for iPad.
为 iPad 创建出色的体验
Like using Apple Pencil for taking notes, markup and illustration.
比如用 Apple Pencil 记笔记、标记和绘图
A reimagined track pad experience
设计一新的触控板体验
that lets you interact with iPad in a whole new way.
让你以全新方式与 iPad 互动
And unmatched AR experiences with ARKit
在 iPad Pro 里 通过 ARKit 和激光雷达扫描仪
and the amazing new LiDAR Scanner in iPad Pro.
享受无与伦比的增强现实体验
All of this combines to put iPad into a class of its own.
这一切都让 iPad 变得独一无二
iPad excels at "every type of input"
iPad 善于支持 “每一种输入端”
and is a "product to do anything and everything."
并且是一款“无所不能的产品”
Which brings us to this year and our new release, iPadOS 14.
因此 我们也会在今年发布 全新的 iPadOS 14
Let's start with experience.
我们先从“体验”开始说起
This year iPadOS delivers unique made-for-iPad designs
今年 iPadOS 会借助 iPad 巨大的多点触控显示屏
that take great advantage of the iPad's large, multi-touch display.
来呈现专为 iPad 设计的独特功能
Now iPad has always been about the apps.
iPad 总是和 app 息息相关
In the beginning, we focused on giving the ecosystem of iPhone apps
一开始时 我们专注为 iPhone app 的生态系统提供
a larger canvas to deliver new and unique experiences.
一个较大的画面 好让它们可以提供新颖独特的体验
This quickly sparked an entirely new set of apps,
这迅速激发了一系列全新 app 的诞生
designed for iPad first,
它们先为 iPad 而设计
with immersive experiences
有着令人沉浸的体验
that transform this magical sheet of glass
能够将一片充满魔力的玻璃
into whatever you needed it to be.
转变成你想要的任何东西
We're proud of the over one million apps on the App Store today
今天的 App Store 有超过 一百万个 app 专为 iPad 而设计
designed just for iPad.
对此我们深感自豪
With customers continuing to push their iPads further than ever before,
由于客户不断地将 iPad 的使用 推向前所未有的高度
we're extending the design language of iPad
因此我们将扩展 iPad 的设计语言
to make apps more streamlined and more powerful.
简化各种 app 而且让它们变得更强大
To give you a live look at these enhancements,
为了让你一睹这些功能提升
I'll hand it over to Josh Shaffer.
我会把这里交给 Josh Shaffer
Thanks, Craig.
Let's take a look at some of the enhancements to iPadOS.
The first thing that you'll notice
你会注意到的第一件事是
are the same redesigned widgets that you saw in iOS 14.
你在 iOS 14 所看到的 一些重新设计的小组件
They look great on iPad as well,
它们在 iPad 上也显得很好看
and they give you information at a glance whenever you go Home.
任何时候回到主屏幕时 它们都能带来信息概览
But let's see some of the improvements in the apps, starting with Photos.
来看看 app 里的改进吧 从照片开始
iPad is the perfect device for browsing your photos.
iPad 是浏览你照片的最佳设备
Its large canvas lets you immerse yourself in all your favorite memories.
它巨大的画面 能让你沉浸在所有喜爱的回忆里
And this year, we're making it even easier to browse and organize your photos
而今年 通过一个全新的边栏 我们使浏览和整理照片
with an all-new sidebar.
变得更便捷了
With just a tap of this button, I can reveal the sidebar,
我只需轻点这个按钮 就可以显示边栏
with all the core functionality of the app in a single location.
App 里的所有核心功能都在同一个地方里
My photos remain front and center,
我的照片依然在最核心的位置上
but now I can quickly tap to move between parts of the app.
现在我可以通过轻点 快速在 app 里的各个功能中切换
The sidebar is a really powerful way to organize your photos too.
这个边栏真的是整理照片的绝佳方式
I can easily drag a photo to the sidebar
我可以轻易地把照片拖动到边栏
and then just drop it to add it to an album.
然后可以把它放添加到相簿
We've brought this sidebar to many apps across iPadOS.
我们把这个边栏 引入了 iPadOS 的很多 app 里
Like Notes,
比如备忘录
where it provides quick and easy access to all your folders.
它可以让你快速且简单地访问所有文件夹
And Files, where we've consolidated navigation into the sidebar
在文件 app 里 我们将导航整合至边栏
for a streamlined new design.
以取得简化的新设计
We've also streamlined the toolbars,
我们也简化了工具栏
adding new drop-down menus that consolidate functions
添加了新的下拉式菜单 它将功能都整合成了
into a single, easy-to-access button.
单一且易于访问的按钮
I can just tap to change views like this.
我只需像这样轻点就可以切换视图
And for even quicker access,
想要更快访问的话
I can just tap and drag to change the sort order, all in a single motion.
我可以轻点并拖动以改变排列顺序 一个操作就搞定
You'll find this same approach across other apps, like Calendar,
你会在其他 app 里发现到 一样的方法 比如在日历里
where we've brought controls into a single toolbar at the top,
我们将控制键带到了顶部的单一工具栏
providing more space for your content
为你的内容提供了更多空间
and a single unified place to access all the app's functionality.
也提供了一个统一的位置 让你可以访问 app 里的所有功能
Finally, Music has been updated
最后 音乐 app 已经升级
to take even better advantage of iPad's large screen.
以便可以更好地利用 iPad 的大屏幕
The sidebar in Music makes it easy to move between views.
音乐 app 里的边栏使切换视图变得容易
I can quickly jump between the new Listen Now and my playlists.
我可以在 Listen Now 和播放列表之间快速跳转
-And once I start playing a song... -["Caution" by The Killers playing]
...I can bring up the brand-new full-screen player,
where I can see rich album art, transport controls and lyrics,
在那里 我可以看到 缤纷的专辑封面、控制键和歌词
-all in one single view. -[song fades]
它们全在一个视图里
And these are just some of the enhancements
这些只是一部分将会来到 iPadOS 的对于 app 的
that are coming to apps in iPadOS.
功能提升
We're really loving these new app designs.
我们真的很喜欢这些 app 的新设计
But there's more,
但不仅如此
starting with Siri.
就从 Siri 开始说起
The new compact Siri design that you heard about in iOS 14
在 iOS 14 里 你所听说的 Siri 新简洁设计
is especially useful on iPad.
在 iPad 里特别实用
Results appear at the bottom right corner,
结果会出现在右下角位置
allowing you to easily reference the app while using Siri.
允许你在调用 Siri 时 更容易地使用 app
And we applied this same approach to other parts of the experience...
我们也把同样的方法 应用到了体验的其他方面
like calls.
比如来电
Now today when you receive a call on iPad, you see this.
[beeps]
Whatever you were working on is suddenly completely covered
无论你当时在做什么 都会被呼入来电的屏幕
with the incoming call screen.
完全覆盖
Not cool.
这可不行
Wouldn't it be nicer if instead you saw this?
如果你看到的是这个 是不是好多了？
[beeps]
Well, that's much better.
没错 这样好多了
Now an incoming call is presented with a compact notification
现在 呼入来电会以简洁的通知方式显示
that doesn't take you out of context.
不会打断你当前的操作
And you can simply tap to answer or flick it away to dismiss.
你只需轻点以接听 或者轻扫以忽略
And this applies to all calls, including those from your iPhone
这也适用于所有来电 包括从你的 iPhone 打来的
or third-party VoIP apps like Skype.
[rings]
And of course we're bringing this to iOS as well.
当然 我们也会将这个带到 iOS
We think our iPhone customers are going to love it.
我们觉得 iPhone 用户会喜欢这个的
Now there's one more key experience we've redesigned for iPad this year,
今年 我们还有一个 为 iPad 重新设计的重要体验
and that's Search.
那就是搜索
Today Search is a full-screen experience,
今天的搜索是一个全屏体验
and sometimes you can lose track of your context.
有时候 这会让你忘记当前操作的进展
So we've redesigned Search with a new, compact design.
所以我们为搜索带来了全新、简洁的设计
You can start a search from anywhere, like the Home Screen
你可以从任何地方开始搜索 比如说从主屏幕
or over any app.
或者任何 app
And this makes it easy to find what you need
这能让你轻松找到想要的东西
without feeling like you've left the app you're working in.
而不会让你觉得 好像脱离了正在使用的 app
But we didn't just redesign it.
但我们绝非只是重新设计了它
We've rebuilt Search from the ground up to be Universal,
我们彻底重建了搜索 将它变为 Universal
becoming a single destination where you can start all of your searches.
这里可以一站式满足你的一切搜索需求
First, we made it better than ever as an app launcher.
首先 我们将它变成 一个更好的 app 启动器
You just start typing a few characters,
只要开始输入一些字符
and you can instantly get to where you're going.
你就可以立即打开想要的 app
It's also great for finding contacts to message or call
它在寻找要发信息或呼叫的 联系人时非常好用
or documents.
寻找文件也是
You can even search directly into apps like Keynote, Messages, Mail or Files.
你甚至可以在 app 里直接搜索 比如 Keynote 讲演、 信息、邮件或文件 app
Or look up information about people or places.
或者查找关于人们或地点的信息
And it's also a great place to start all of your web searches as well.
它也是你开启所有网络搜索的绝佳地方
As soon as you start typing,
只要你一开始输入
you get relevant suggestions to complete your search.
就会得到相关建议来完成你搜索
And you can get to your web search results with just a tap.
而你可以通过一个轻点 去往你的网络搜索结果
And Search now makes navigating to your favorite websites
现在的搜索 让你轻松导航至所喜爱的网站
just as easy as launching an app.
就和启动 app 一样容易
Just type a few letters and the top hit will take you right to Safari.
只需输入几个字母 出现的首个结果 就会直接将你带到 Safari 浏览器
So those are some of our updates to the iPad experience.
这些就是我们 iPad 体验的几个升级
And of course, you also get the new widgets
当然 你也会得到新的小组件
and all the other great app enhancements from iOS 14.
以及所有 iOS 14 所包含的 app 功能提升
Next, we want to push forward your ability to express yourself creatively
接下来 我们要提升你表达创意能力
with improvements to Apple Pencil.
请看 Apple Pencil 的改进
Apple Pencil is a game-changing tool
Apple Pencil 是变革性的工具
that turns iPad into a professional drawing canvas,
它将 iPad 变成了一个专业的绘图画板
a great way to mark up and sign documents
一个标记和签署文件的绝佳方式
and the ultimate note-taking device.
以及一个终极的记笔记设备
What many people love most about taking notes with Apple Pencil
在使用 Apple Pencil 记笔记这方面 绝大多数人最爱的一点就是
is how they can express themselves in a free-form way.
他们可以通过自由发挥来表达自己
Mixing handwriting and drawings can be the best way to capture your thoughts.
将手写和绘图混在一起 可能是捕捉你想法的最佳方式
Now the challenge is when you want to change things afterwards.
可问题出现在你之后想更改东西时
Here, working with handwriting just isn't as easy as with typed text.
使用手写不像键入文本那样简单
Now, we sometimes take it for granted,
我们有时会觉得很理所应该
but with typed text it's so easy to select,
但键入文本非常容易取词
copy and paste into another document,
复制和粘贴去另一份文件
or even just make space for more text.
甚至可以为更多文字腾出空间
Well, this year, we're going to make handwriting just as easy
可今年 我们会让手写变得一样容易
and just as powerful.
一样强大
But that's not all.
不过不只是这样
Our customers tell us that once they have an Apple Pencil in their hand,
我们的用户告诉我们 一旦他们手上握着 Apple Pencil
they don't want to put it away.
他们就不想再放下了
So this year, we're bringing Scribble to iPad.
所以今年 我们把涂文字带到了 iPad 上
So you can handwrite into any text field,
这样你就可以在任何文本框手写了
and it will automatically be converted to text.
它会自动转换成文本
To show you all of this in action,
为了向你展示如何做到这一切
I'd like to welcome Jenny Chen for a live demo.
我很荣幸邀请到了 Jenny Chen 来进行现场演示
Thanks, Craig.
I'm really excited to show you some great new features we have
for Apple Pencil and iPadOS this year.
Apple Pencil 和 iPadOS 今年的新功能
One of the great parts about taking notes with the Apple Pencil
用 Apple Pencil 做笔记 一个很大的优点
is that it really lets you work in a free-form way.
就是你可以自由自在地发挥
I can just start writing anywhere.
我可以在屏幕任何地方下笔
And it's not just about text.
而且不只是文字
I can also express myself with drawings or shapes.
我还可以通过绘画和图形来表达自己
But sometimes you want that more professional, cleaned-up look.
但有时你希望可以营造出那种 更加专业、工整的感觉
So now, when I draw a simple shape and pause at the end,
所以 现在当我画一个简单的图形时 在收笔前稍作停留的话
it'll automatically convert to that ideal shape.
它就会被转换成那种完美的形状
And we're smart about it, retaining the same size
我们在设计上很巧妙 它会保留同样的尺寸
and angle that you drew it at.
以及你绘制时的角度
In addition to shapes,
除了图形之外
we've also made huge improvements to our handwriting recognition.
我们也在手写识别方面取得了显著进展
So now, when I write, I can easily make a selection
现在我书写的时候可以轻易进行选取
using the same gestures that I use for typed text.
只需使用与在键入文本时同样的手势
I can double tap to select a word or double tap again to select a line.
我可以轻点两下 来选取一个字 或者再轻点两下 选取一整行
Thanks to our advanced, on-device machine learning,
多亏了我们先进的设备端机器学习技术
you'll notice how we can select the handwriting
你会注意到我们可以选取你的手写内容
while avoiding the drawings nearby.
同时避开周围的图画
Now that I have the selection,
在选取好了之后
I can easily change the color or move it around the document.
我可以很容易就改变颜色 或者移动到文档的任何位置
It's also perfectly easy for me to make space for more room to write.
我也可以不费吹灰之力 就腾出空间来书写更多内容
We think that this will make note-taking with the Apple Pencil even better.
我们认为这会让用 Apple Pencil 记笔记 变得更加好用
Now, you don't even have to put it down when you want to do something else.
现在 当你想要做其他事情时 你甚至都不需要将笔放下
Let's say you want to search for "Edison bulbs" in Safari.
譬如你想要在 Safari 浏览器 搜索“Edison bulbs”
Using Scribble, I can just write directly into the text field...
我可以利用涂文字直接在文本框书写
and it automatically gets converted to typed text.
It also works in any text field,
这种功能在任何文本框都可以使用
so I can easily add a new Reminder
我可以把一个新提醒事项
to my shared Reminders list with my husband.
轻松添加到我和我丈夫的共享提醒事项中
I've also been learning Chinese,
我也一直在学习中文
so I want to surprise him with some of my progress and skills.
我想秀一下我的学习进展和汉语能力 给他个惊喜
I'll use Scratch to delete "lights."
我会划掉来删除“灯”
And then I can use Scribble to write "new" and then "light fixture" in Chinese.
然后我会利用涂文字用英文写“新” 后面跟着中文的“灯具”
You'll notice how Scribble recognizes both English and Chinese in the same line.
你会注意到涂文字可以在一行之中 同时识别英文和中文
And what's awesome is that we can build on this technology
很棒的一点是 我们可以以这项技术为基础
to deliver other great features, like Data Detectors.
从而推出其他超赞的功能 譬如数据探测器
We can automatically detect what you write,
我们可以自动检测到你书写的内容
like phone numbers, so I can make a phone call.
譬如电话号码 这样我就能拨打电话
Or addresses, so I can look up directions.
或者地址 这样我就可以查询路线
We can use these features together to do even more with your handwriting.
把这些功能融合在一起 我们可以用手写输入做更多事情
Let's say I wanted to use my handwriting in another app.
譬如我想在另一个 app 上 使用我手写的文字
I can easily select what I want,
我可以选取我想要的内容
tap the new Copy as Text from the callout bar,
轻点调出菜单中的“复制为文本”
and then paste it into an app like Pages.
然后在 Pages 文稿这样的 app 中粘贴
And it's automatically converted to typed text.
内容会被自动转换成键入文本
We're really excited about these awesome new features.
这些了不起的新功能让我们感到很兴奋
And we think it will let you do even more with the Apple Pencil.
如此一来 你可以用 Apple Pencil 做更多事情
Thanks, Jenny.
多谢你了 Jenny
So those are the enhancements to Pencil.
刚才为大家介绍的是 Pencil 的改进
Just one part of an amazing release,
新发布的精彩功能不止于此
with Scribble for handwriting into any text field,
在任何文本框都可以进行涂文字输入
a whole new way to work with your handwritten notes,
手写记录笔记的一个全新的方法
broad enhancements to the app experience,
对于 app 体验的广泛提升
and of course, iPad users also benefit
当然了 iPad 用户也能从
from the great features you already saw in iOS 14
iOS 14 已经拥有的那些很棒的功能
and much more that we didn't have time to talk about.
以及我们没有时间详谈的很多功能中受益
So that's iOS and iPadOS.
这就是 iOS 和 iPadOS
Next, let's talk about AirPods.
接下来 我们来聊一下 AirPods
From the one-click setup
从一键设置
to the automatic pairing with all your devices
到和你全部的设备自动配对
to how they pause your audio when you take them out,
到摘下它们时暂停播放
people love the magical experience that AirPods deliver.
人们对于 AirPods 所带来的神奇体验 深爱不已
Now we're bringing even more magic to AirPods.
现在我们给 AirPods 带来了更多神奇功能
To tell you all about it, here's Mary-Ann Ionascu.
有请 Mary-Ann Ionascu 来为大家详细介绍
Thanks, Craig.
We have some amazing updates coming to AirPods,
starting with Automatic Switching.
我们先从自动切换说起
AirPods will now seamlessly move between your devices
AirPods 现在可以在设备之间无缝切换
without you having to manually switch them.
无需手动操作
Let's say you just finished listening to a podcast
譬如你刚刚听完播客
and you pick up your iPad to watch a show.
你拿起 iPad 打算看个节目
AirPods will magically switch over.
AirPods 会神奇地切换过去
And later you start a video conference on your Mac.
之后你在 Mac 上开视频会议
AirPods will automatically switch again.
AirPods 会再一次自动切换过去
-[ringing] -And if a phone call comes in,
如果有一通电话打进来
the audio in your AirPods will route right back to your phone.
AirPods 的音频会切换回手机上
We also have an exciting new feature coming to AirPods Pro:
AirPods Pro 还会为你带来一项 非常激动人心的新功能
spatial audio.
空间音频功能
You know the experience of being in a movie theater
众所周知 身处电影院中
with a state-of-the-art surround sound system,
体验的是先进环绕音响系统
one where the sound not only comes from in front of you...
在那里 声音不止从你面前
-[tone pulsing] -...but also from the left, the right,
behind, and even from above you?
Well, we are thrilled to bring that same immersive experience to AirPods Pro.
我们很兴奋可以将同样令人沉浸的体验 带到 AirPods Pro 上
But it turns out it's a lot harder to do
但实现起来要比想象中困难很多
when you only have a single earbud in each ear.
因为每只耳朵上只能佩戴一只耳机
So our team created advanced spatial audio algorithms for AirPods Pro
所以 我们的团队为 AirPods Pro 创造了一种先进的空间音频功能算法
that replicate the movie theater experience.
来复制影院体验
By applying directional audio filters
通过加入定向音频过滤器
and subtly adjusting the frequencies each ear receives,
以及对每个耳朵所接受的频率进行微调
we can place sounds virtually anywhere in space...
[high-speed vehicles passing]
...creating an immersive surround sound experience.
并创造一种令人沉浸的音频体验
But to truly deliver on this promise, we had to factor in real-life situations.
但为了真正达成这种效果 我们需要将真实情景考虑在内
First, people move their heads.
首先 人们的脑袋不会纹丝不动
For an authentic surround sound experience,
要想实现真实的环绕声音体验
you need the sound field to stay fixed
你需要声场保持在固定的位置
so the voice feels like it's coming from the actor
这样才会感觉声音来自于演员
and not some random point in space.
而不是空间中随便一个地方
So we use the accelerometer and gyroscopes in AirPods Pro
所以我们用了 AirPods Pro 上的 加速感应器和陀螺仪
to track the motion of your head,
来追踪头部的动作
remapping the sound field so it stays anchored to your device,
并重新映射声场 这样它就会与设备牢牢固定在一起
even as your head moves.
就算你的头部移动也没关系
And it's not only your head that can move,
而会移动的不止是你的头部
but you might move your iPad or iPhone as well.
你还可能会移动你的 iPad 或者 iPhone
That's why we constantly compare the motion data
这是为何我们会不断比对
from your head and your screen
头部和屏幕的动作数据
to understand how they are moving in relation to each other.
来了解它们是如何相对移动的
So if your bus turns the corner or your plane banks,
所以 就算你乘坐的公交车转弯 或者飞机倾斜机身
the sound stays in sync.
声音仍然会保持同步
The result is a surround sound experience
这样就能为你带来环绕声音的体验
that keeps you in the middle of the action,
让你保持身临其境的感觉
no matter where you go.
无论你去往何处
Spatial audio for AirPods Pro will work with content encoded in 5.1, 7.1,
AirPods Pro 的空间音频功能适用于 5.1 或 7.1 声道编码的内容
and even Dolby Atmos.
甚至包括杜比全景声
Thanks, Mary-Ann.
谢谢你 Mary-Ann
I've been using the new spatial audio,
我体验过空间音频功能
and I think you're all really gonna love it.
我觉得你们都会对其爱不释手的
All right. Next let's head to the Fitness Center
好 接下来我们要去 Fitness Center
to hear the latest on watchOS from Kevin.
["I'm Getting Tired" by Jacknife Lee playing]
[song ends]
Thanks, Craig. Since we launched Apple Watch,
it's completely redefined what a watch can do,
这个产品完全重新定义了 手表能做什么
and this has been incredibly meaningful work.
这项工作对我们来说意义非凡
Apple Watch not only helps you stay connected and active,
Apple Watch 不仅帮你 与关心的人紧密联系 并保有活力
it's become an intelligent guardian of your health,
它还成为了你健康的智能守护者
enabling you to take an ECG, detect falls and call emergency services for you.
可以给你做心电图 进行摔倒检测 并替你拨打紧急服务电话
It's impacting lives in ways that were inconceivable five years ago.
它对你的生活的影响 在五年前是不可想象的
The power of Apple Watch is not only its built-in features,
Apple Watch 的厉害之处 不仅在于其内置的功能
but how developers have personalized it for you.
还在于开发者为你实现了个性化订制
We introduced the App Store in watchOS 6,
我们在 watchOS 6 中引入了 App Store
and there are now over 20,000 watchOS apps available.
至今已有超过两万个 watchOS app 可以下载
These apps bring the information you care about most
这些 app 让你最关心的信息
to just a glance at your watch face.
只需扫一眼表盘即可获知
We're taking this even further in watchOS 7,
在 watchOS 7 中 我们做到了更进一步
starting with complications.
从复杂功能开始
Until today, an app could appear in only one spot at a time on a watch face.
以往 一个 app 只能同时出现在表盘上的一个位置
In watchOS 7 developers can enable multiple complications,
在 watchOS 7 中 开发者可以开启 多个复杂功能
making even more richly personal watch faces.
制作更加丰富的个性化表盘
So if you like to use Dawn Patrol for surfing,
如果你冲浪时喜欢用 Dawn Patrol app
you can create your own surf watch,
你可以创建一个你自己的冲浪手表
including water temperature, swell and wind speed predictions
来显示水温、海浪大小和风速预测
for your favorite beach.
为你最爱的海滩来显示这些数据
Or new parents can use Glow Baby
新手父母用户可以使用 Glow Baby app
to see nap, changing and feeding times all on one face.
在一个表盘上就可以查看宝宝 小睡、更换尿布以及喂奶时间
While Nike Run Club can display stats like pace from your last run
Nike Run Club app 可以显示诸如配速等 上次跑步的数据
and your weekly run goals.
以及你每周的跑步目标
We're also bringing rich complications to more faces,
我们也把丰富的复杂功能 带到了更多的表盘上
including a fresh Chronograph face
包括全新计时码表表盘
with an integrated tachymeter
它集成了测速仪
and an updated Extra Large face
以及更新过的大文字表盘
with a huge, rich complication right in the center.
巨大、丰富的复杂功能显示在中间
And Configuring Watch Faces has been redesigned
配置表盘这项功能被重新设计
so you can easily select which information you'd like to see.
这样你就可以容易地选取想要看到的信息
As developers, with watchOS 7
开发者可以通过 watchOS 7
you can now build your rich complications with native SwiftUI.
用原生 SwiftUI 构建丰富的复杂功能
While there are so many ways to configure watch faces,
虽然配置表盘有如此多的的方式
you may not have yet gone in and set these up for yourself yet.
你可能不知要从何下手
That's okay.
没关系
With watchOS 7 we're making it super easy to share watch faces,
在 watchOS 7 之中 我们让表盘共享变得超级容易
so you can discover a face that works perfectly for you.
这样你就可以找到一块最适合你的表盘
To do this, we're introducing Face Sharing.
因此，我们推出了表盘共享
You'll be able to discover curated faces with third-party apps on the App Store,
你可以通过 App Store 发现 精选的第三方 app 的表盘
or discover a new favorite watch face right on a website,
或者直接在网站上发现中意的表盘
or receive watch faces directly from friends and family.
或者直接从朋友或家人那里 接收所共享的表盘
Let's take a look at how this works.
我们来看看这是怎样实现的
When you see a watch face you'd like, you just press "Add Apple Watch Face."
当你看到喜欢的表盘 可以按下“Add Apple Watch Face”
If the watch face uses some apps that you don't have yet,
如果表盘上会用到一些 你还没有下载的 app
you'll be offered each one right here so you can easily get them if you like.
这些 app 都会在这里显示出来 这样你喜欢，就可以下载它们
And the new face appears right on your watch.
新的表盘就会出现在你的手表上
If you'd like to share a face you've created yourself,
如果你想共享你自己创建的表盘
that's also really easy.
也很简单
Just long press on the face,
只要长按表盘
tap "Share," pick a contact and send.
轻点“共享” 然后选择一个联系人发送就好
Developers can offer preconfigured watch faces right from their apps.
开发者可以在他们的 app 上提供 事先配置好的表盘
You can even share watch faces across social media.
你甚至可以在社交媒体上共享表盘
It's a great way for the community of Apple Watch wearers to connect
这样能利于 Apple Watch 用户之间 连接互动
and help each other discover all the amazing things Apple Watch is capable of.
并帮助彼此发现所有 Apple Watch 可以带来的惊喜
Next, let's talk about Maps.
接下来 我们来了解一下地图
Maps is great for walking, driving and transit directions,
地图很适合步行、开车以及公交出行
and now in watchOS, just like in iOS 14,
正如同 iOS 14， watchOS 现在
you can get cycling directions.
也可以提供骑行导航
You'll see a variety of routes
你会看到各种路线
with information like time, distance
所提供的信息包括时间、距离
and whether there are bike lanes.
以及是否有自行车专用道
You can preview travel time and elevation changes
你可以预览行程时间、海拔变化
and navigate with turn-by-turn directions that are large and easy to read.
并通过直观易读的分段路向指示进行导航
Maps can direct you to dismount and walk your bike
地图指示你下车推车行走
or even take the stairs to save time.
甚至采取爬楼梯路线 以便节省时间
You can also search for and add places optimized for cyclists,
你也可以搜索并添加 为骑车人优化过的地点
like bike repair shops.
[chimes]
Now to tell you about how we're advancing Workouts,
现在我们要聊一聊我们是如何将 体能训练做得更好的
please welcome Julz Arney.
请欢迎 Julz Arney
Thanks, Kevin.
The Workout app uses algorithms that are smartly tuned
to track all aspects of your training.
来追踪训练的各个方面
It's one of the most used apps on Apple Watch,
这是 Apple Watch 上 使用率最高的 app 之一
and we've continued to add support for new workout types every year.
我们每年都会向 app 中 添加新的健身方式
-And in watchOS 7 we're adding Dance. -[dance music playing]
Dance is a total body workout that's great for your heart.
舞蹈是全身性的运动 对你的心脏非常有利
It makes you more fit and flexible, and you're guaranteed to have fun.
让你的身材和柔韧性都变好 你也一定会乐在其中
Whether you're doing Hip Hop, Latin, Bollywood, or simply Cardio Dance,
无论你是跳街舞、拉丁舞、宝莱坞舞蹈 或者只是有氧舞蹈
the Workout app now tracks
体能训练 app 现在都能追踪
some of the world's most popular styles of dance for fitness.
一些世界上最流行的健身舞蹈风格
Getting the most accurate credit for Dance presented a unique challenge.
精确计算舞蹈消耗的卡路里数 是一项独特的挑战
Arm movements aren't always repetitive or synchronized with leg movements
手臂动作不会总是重复 或者与腿部动作协调一致
like in running and walking.
就像跑步与行走一样
The solution was to use advanced sensor fusion.
解决方案是使用高级传感器融合
[music continues]
In Dance, we combine data from the accelerometer and the gyroscope
to detect the difference between dancing with just your arms...
来监测只有手部动作…
just your lower body...
只有下半身动作…
or when you put it all together and dance with your entire body.
或者全部动作都加起来 整个身体都在跳舞之间的区别
Then we add in heart rate data
然后我们会加入心率数据
for the most accurate calorie burn calculations.
从而得出最准确的卡路里燃烧计算
watchOS 7 also tracks accurate calories for Core Training,
watchOS 7 也可以在核心训练中 精确追踪卡路里消耗
those exercises for your abs and back,
比如腹肌和背部训练
Functional Strength Training,
功能性力量训练
a workout type that helps you get stronger and move better for everyday activities,
一种帮助你增强体力 并且让你的日常活动更加自如的体能训练
and also Cooldowns
以及整理放松
to add on to another workout
附加在其他训练之上
when you want to continue with easy moves and stretches
用轻松的动作和拉伸来继续运动
as you bring your heart rate and breathing back to normal.
让你的心跳和呼吸回归正常
Of course, you can track your progress for any of these new workouts
当然 追踪这些新的训练方式的进展情况
inside the Activity app on iPhone,
可以在 iPhone 的健身记录 app 中进行
which is completely redesigned in watchOS 7.
这个 app 在 watchOS 7 中 被完全重新设计
The app now features a new Summary tab
此 app 现在推出了新的摘要标签
that gives you an easy way to see your activity history,
让你可以很容易就看到活动记录
workouts and trends, all in one seamless view.
体能训练与趋势 全都集中在一页
With a new focus on easy navigation and summary metrics,
因为关注点转向了简易浏览和摘要数据
the app is getting a new name as well:
这个 app 也有了一个新的名字
[music continues]
Fitness.
健身
Back to you, Kevin.
现在把画面交还给你 Kevin
-[record scratches] -[music ends]
Thanks, Julz.
多谢了 Julz
Apple Watch helps you meet not only your fitness goals,
Apple Watch 不仅能帮你达到健身目标
but also helps support your health
还可以支持你的健康
with features such as Cycle Tracking, the Breathe app, and Noise notifications.
在经期跟踪、呼吸 app、噪声提示 这些功能的辅助下
And we're going to be adding even more capabilities this year in watchOS 7.
我们今年会在 watchOS 7 上 添加更多新的功能
We'd like to share a couple of them with you today,
今天我们想要跟你们分享几个
starting with one of the most-requested features for Apple Watch:
从 Apple Watch 上呼声最大的功能开始
tracking your sleep.
追踪你的睡眠状况
To tell you about this, over to Vera Carr.
让 Vera Carr 来讲讲这个功能
Thanks, Kevin.
There are many ways to look at sleep: scores, advanced monitoring,
or sleep cycle analysis.
或者睡眠周期分析
We are taking a more holistic approach to sleep
我们在睡眠上采取了更加全面的方法
by leveraging the devices you use every day
利用你每天都在使用的设备
to not only track your sleep
不仅可以追踪你的睡眠
but to support you in actually meeting your sleep duration goal.
而且可以支持你达到你的睡眠时间目标
That starts with choosing not only when you would like to wake up in the morning,
首先 你不仅可以选择早上何时起床
but also when you'd like to go to bed.
也可以选择何时入睡
For most of us, setting a goal is easy.
对我们大多数人来讲 设定目标很容易
But getting to bed on time, that's the hard part.
按时入睡才是难题
Experts say that establishing a bedtime routine
helps the body transition from wakefulness to sleep.
可以帮助身体从清醒状态转换到入睡状态
So we are offering Wind Down.
正因为如此 我们推出了助眠
It can help you get to bed on time by minimizing distractions
它可以通过尽量减少干扰 来帮助你准时上床
and creating a personalized routine.
并创造个性化的睡前习惯
Let's look at how this works.
我们来看看具体是怎样的
In the evening, ahead of your bedtime,
在晚间 你的入睡时间之前
your phone can display the Wind Down screen
你的手机会显示助眠屏幕
to help you transition mentally before you go to bed.
在你入睡前帮助你酝酿睡意
It creates a calm lock screen experience and turns on Do Not Disturb for you.
它会创建一个令人平静的锁屏体验 并且替你打开勿扰模式
You can also set up shortcuts
你也可以设置快捷指令
for simple things you may like to do to help you prepare for bed.
加入一些能帮助你入睡的简单事情
These might include using your favorite meditation app
比如使用你最喜欢的冥想 app
or playing relaxing music.
或播放令人放松的音乐
Once it's time for bed,
一旦到了睡眠时间
your screen will dim and your watch will go into Sleep Mode,
你的屏幕会变暗 你的手表就会进入睡眠模式
which looks like this.
就像这样一样
The screen will be off during time in bed so it won't bother you,
屏幕在你睡眠期间会关闭 所以不会对你造成打扰
and a tap displays this simple face.
轻点一下就会出现如此简约的表盘
When it's time to wake up,
当起床时间到了的时候
you have a selection of gentle and effective alarm sounds,
你可以选择轻柔但有效的闹铃
or a silent Taptic-only wake-up alarm so you don't disturb your partner.
或者无声的仅有触感的起床闹铃 这样你就不会打扰到枕边人
Once you're up, you'll see a friendly greeting easing you into the day.
It also shows your battery level
so you can remember to charge in the morning.
这样你就会记得在早上充电
Apple Watch tracks your sleep
Apple Watch 追踪你的睡眠
using a machine-learning model that senses your motion
用的是一种机器学习模型 可以感应到你的动作
and even interprets the micro-movements
甚至去理解你吸气呼气之间
caused by the rise and fall of your breath,
所造成的微动作
providing signals for when you're awake and when you're asleep.
提供你在入睡和清醒状态下的信号
There's an updated Sleep section in the Health app,
我们在健康 app 中的睡眠状况区域 做了更新
including a view of your trends over time.
包括查看你长久以来的趋势
Sleep Schedules, Wind Down, and Sleep Mode
睡眠计划、助眠以及睡眠模式
are also available on iPhone, without a watch, in iOS 14.
不需要手表也可以在安装 iOS 14 的 iPhone 上使用
We know you'll enjoy using your watch throughout the day
我们知道你会在白天享受使用手表
and now throughout the night.
如今你也会在晚上继续享受了
Thanks, Vera.
谢谢 Vera
In addition to sleep keeping you healthy,
除了让你保持身体健康的睡眠状况
there's another preventative-care item that's so important, particularly now:
还有另一项预防保健的功能 它非常重要 尤其是在现在
handwashing.
洗手
In watchOS 7,
watchOS 7 里面
Apple Watch is the first watch to deliver automatic detection
Apple Watch 是第一个能够自动检测 你何时开始洗手
when you start washing your hands and sensing of how long you actually wash.
以及感应你洗了多久的智能手表
Our approach here is using machine-learning models
我们采取的办法就是使用机器学习模式
to determine motion which appears to be handwashing
来测定貌似是洗手的动作
and then use audio to confirm the sound of running water
然后使用音频来确定流水声
or squishing soap on your hands.
或往手上挤洗手液的声音
During this, you'll get a little coaching to do a good job.
在此期间 你会得到一点小指导 来教你好好洗手
You'll see a countdown, along with haptics and sounds,
你会看到表盘上的倒计时 感应到触觉 听到声音
to make sure you wash as long as you're supposed to.
来确保你洗手的时间符合标准
If you pause early, there's a polite note to keep washing.
如果你早早停下 Watch 会发出 礼貌的提醒 要你继续洗手
And when you're done, you'll see, hear and feel it.
That's just some of what's coming this year in watchOS 7,
这只是今年要问世的 watchOS 7 的 一部分功能而已
including discovering and sharing faces, new workout types,
包括发现并共享表盘、新类型的体能训练
sleep and handwashing detection,
睡眠状况和洗手检测
and other new capabilities like Siri language translation.
还有其他类似 Siri 语言翻译的新功能
And that's Apple Watch.
这就是 Apple Watch
It's time for you to join Craig again
大家再次欢迎 Craig
to talk about something that's important to all of us.
来讲讲对我们所有人都很重要的事
Here we go!
开始吧！
["I'm Getting Tired" by Jacknife Lee playing]
[song ends]
At Apple, we believe privacy is a fundamental human right.
在 Apple 这里 我们相信 隐私是每个人的基本权利
So we build it into our products from the beginning of the design process.
于是从设计过程的最开始 我们就把它融入到了我们的产品里
Privacy matters now more than ever.
如今 隐私具有着前所未有的重要性
And because our devices contain our most sensitive information,
因为我们的设备里 包含着我们最敏感的信息
all of our product work is grounded in a set of privacy principles.
我们所有的产品工作都建立在 一系列隐私原则的基础上
First, data minimization.
第一 数据最小化
We use innovative technologies and techniques
我们使用创新性技术和工艺
to minimize the personal data we or anyone else can access.
将我们或其他任何人能获得的 私人数据最小化
Second, on-device intelligence.
第二 设备端智能技术
We avoid data collection
我们避免数据收集
by processing as much of your information on your device as we can
方法就是尽可能在你的设备上 处理你的信息
rather than sending it to a server.
而不是把它发给服务器
Third, security.
第三 安全
Security protections are foundational to everything we do in privacy.
安全保护是我们为隐私所做的 一切努力的基础
And finally, transparency and control.
最后是透明度和管控
It helps you better understand the data being collected
这能帮助大家更好地理解被收集的数据
so that you can make your own choices about how that data is used.
这样大家就能自己选择该如何使用该数据
These principles come together across our products,
这些原则凝聚在我们的产品中
in our hardware, our software and our services.
在我们的硬件、软件和服务中，
At the end of the day, they result in great privacy and great ease of use.
最终 这些原则会带来更强的隐私保护 和极大的易用性
A powerful example of this is Sign in with Apple,
这方面的一个有力例证就是 通过 Apple 登录
which is designed for simplicity, security and privacy.
它的设计目的是为了追求简洁 安全和隐私
And since we launched it last year,
自从我们去年发布它之后
users have created over 200 million accounts
用户们已经创建了超过两亿个账户
across a wide variety of apps and websites.
遍及各种 app 和网站
And developers are seeing great usage when they adopt it.
开发者们使用它时看到了强大的使用价值
For example,
比如说
Kayak has integrated Sign in with Apple
Kayak app 整合了 通过 Apple 登录功能
and found that their users are now two times more likely to use it
发现比起通过其他登录方式 其用户现在使用它的可能性
than any other sign-in provider.
翻了一倍
Now, one thing we hear a lot with Sign in with Apple
现在 关于通过 Apple 登录 我们经常听到的一点
is that people wish they could convert their existing accounts to use it.
就是人们希望他们能转换现有的账户 变成使用通过 Apple 登录
So this year we're going to enable developers to let you do just that.
今年我们会让开发者们实现 大家的这个愿望
When you upgrade, you get the ease of use
当大家升级时 你们就能使用
and built-in security of Sign in with Apple
通过 Apple 登录并享受其内置的安全
while keeping the account that you already have.
同时保留大家已有的账户
This is another big year of privacy improvements in our products.
今年是我们产品隐私性能提高的 又一个重要年度
And to tell you more, here's Katie Skinner and Erik Neuenschwander.
现在有请 Katie Skinner 和 Erik Neuenschwander 做更多讲解
Thanks, Craig.
First let's talk about location.
This year we're continuing to give you even more control.
In addition to the option of sharing your precise location,
除了分享你的精确定位的选项
you will have the option to only share your approximate location with apps.
你将能够选择只和 app 分享 你的大致位置
We're also making changes for mic and camera
我们也将对麦克风和相机做出改变
so you always know when you're recording.
In addition to requiring your permission,
this year we're adding more visibility for current or recent mic or camera use.
今年我们要为目前或最近使用麦克风 或相机添加更多可视性
So if an app uses either one, we'll indicate that in the status bar.
所以如果一个 app 使用了其中之一 状态栏里会显示这点
[Katie] Next, let's talk about tracking.
Safari's Intelligent Tracking Prevention has been really successful on the web.
Safari 浏览器的智能防跟踪功能 在网络世界一直非常成功
And this year, we wanted to help you with tracking in apps.
今年 我们想在 app 跟踪功能方面 帮助大家
We believe tracking should always be transparent and under your control.
我们认为跟踪应该始终是透明的 在用户的控制之下的
So moving forward,
所以我们更进一步
App Store policy will require apps to ask before tracking you
App Store 的政策将要求 app 在跟踪你之前先问你
across apps and websites owned by other companies.
其中包括其他公司拥有的 app 和网站
[Erik] Last, let's talk about app privacy.
最后 我们来谈谈隐私政策
Today we require that apps have a privacy policy.
今天我们要求 app 要有隐私政策
Wouldn't it be great to even more quickly and easily see
在你下载一个 app 之前能够 更快、更容易地看到
a summary of an app's privacy practices before you download it?
其隐私实践的总结 这不是很棒吗？
Now, where have we seen something like that before?
我们以前在哪里见过类似这样的东西吗？
For food, you have nutrition labels.
食物有营养成分表
You can see if it's packed with protein or loaded with sugar, or maybe both,
在买下某个食物前 你可以看到它是 含有大量蛋白质还是大量糖分
all before you buy it.
又或者两者皆有
So we thought it would be great to have something similar for apps.
所以我们认为让 app 拥有类似的东西 是件很好的事
We're going to require each developer to self-report their practices.
我们将要求每个开发者 自我报告他们的实践
[Katie] We'll show you what they tell us.
把他们告诉我们的展示给大家
You can see if the developer is collecting a little bit of data on you
大家就能看到这个开发者是要从你身上 收集一点数据
or a lot of data,
还是很多数据
or if they're sharing data with other companies to track you,
还是他们是否 在和其他公司分享数据来跟踪你
and much more.
还有更多其他的
[Erik] We're going to put this information
on product pages in the App Store.
So for each app, you can see highlights of their privacy information
所以对于每个 app 在下载前你就能看到
before you download it.
它们突出显示的隐私信息
And we're going to include this in all of our App Stores.
我们所有的 App Store 都将包括这个
Back over to you, Craig.
Craig 我们把画面交还给你
Thanks, Katie and Erik.
谢谢 Katie 和 Erik
These are some of the ways we're strengthening the privacy of our platforms
这些是我们要加强我们平台隐私 和引入新功能来给用户
and bringing new features to give users even more control.
更多管控权的几个方式
And one of the places where privacy matters most is your home.
隐私最具重要性的几个地方之一 就是你们的家
Like most of you,
和大多数人一样
in the past few months I've spent more time at home than I ever imagined.
在过去的几个月里 我在家待的时间 超过了我的想象
It's more clear than ever just how important it is
比以往更清晰的是 住在一个
to live in a home where the technology just works.
能应用现代科技的家中有多么重要
That brings us to some great new features we're bringing to the home this year.
这引导大家来了解我们今年要给 家庭添加的几个很棒的新功能
All of these features share a few key attributes.
所有这些功能都具有几个关键属性
First, anything we develop for the home should be easy,
首先 我们为家庭开发的一切 从初始设置到日常使用
from initial setup to everyday use,
都应该是简单的
just like how a tap of your iPhone can automatically configure an Apple TV.
例如轻点 iPhone 就能自动配置 Apple TV
Second, home products should never compromise your privacy.
第二 家庭产品绝对不该在隐私方面 做出让步
That's why your Siri requests use a random identifier, not your Apple ID.
所以你的 Siri 要求使用随机标示符 而不是你的 Apple ID
And finally, your devices should all work better together,
最后 你的设备一起工作的效果应该更好
like how AirPlay lets you share from your iPhone straight to the TV.
例如 隔空播放能够直接 把你 iPhone 上的画面分享给 TV
And when things are easy, private and work together seamlessly,
当一切变得简单、隐私而且无缝协作时
your home is more enjoyable,
你的家也会变得更有乐趣
whether you're watching TV, listening to music
无论你是在看电视、听音乐
or getting the most out of your smart devices.
还是尽情使用你的智能设备
To tell you more about what we have in store for the home,
接下来有请 Yah Cason 来给大家讲解更多
let me pass it to Yah Cason.
关于家庭方面的新功能
Thanks, Craig.
Let's start by talking about the smart home.
With HomeKit, we've given developers a robust framework
有 HomeKit 的协助 我们给了开发者们 一个稳固的框架
to create smart home accessories that are remarkably easy to set up
来创建智能家居配件 这些附件都能非常轻易地被设置
all while being end-to-end encrypted to your Apple devices.
同时端到端地加密到你的 Apple 设备
Already there's a rich ecosystem of devices available.
我们已经有一个丰富的可用设备生态系统
But we want to make it even easier to build products
但我们想让它能够更轻易地打造
that work across more homes.
能在更多家庭发挥作用的产品
So we formed an alliance
于是我们组成联盟
and partnered with Amazon, Google and other industry leaders
和 Amazon、Google 和其他行业领袖 联手合作
to define a new interoperability standard for the smart home.
来为智能家居定义一个 新的可彼此协作的操作性标准
We open-sourced HomeKit
我们开放了 HomeKit 的源代码
to ensure its ease of use and privacy are core to this effort.
来确保它的易用性和隐私 是我们所有努力的核心
And any accessory using HomeKit or this new standard
任何使用 HomeKit 或这个新标准的配件
will work incredibly well across all your Apple devices.
将在你所有的 Apple 的设备上顺畅运作
And you control it all in the Home app,
你能够在家庭 app 上操控这一切
the most secure way to manage your smart home.
这种管理智能家居的办法最安全
Adding new devices to your home has never been easier.
给家里添加新设备变得前所未有的简单
Simply tap or scan to set up an accessory.
只需轻点或扫描来设置配件
And in iOS 14, after you add an accessory,
在 iOS 14 中 添加完配件后
the Home app will now suggest useful automations
家庭 app 会建议有用的自动化
so you can immediately put your new device to work for you.
这样你就能立即使用你的新设备了
Automations are rules that set your home to autopilot,
自动化是让你的家自动运行的规则
like automatically turning on your porch lights when motion is detected
比如说检测到动作时自动打开门廊灯
or having the garage door open as you arrive home.
或者当你到家时自动打开车库门
And now when you open the Home app,
当你打开家庭 app 时
you'll see a new visual status right up top
你会看到顶部出现了一个新的可视化状态
that prioritizes the accessories which most need your attention.
把你最需要注意的配件放到优先位置
You can easily see if you've left a door unlocked or the lights on
你很容易就能看到自己是否忘了锁门 或者关灯
and quickly control them.
并快速控制它们
Let's take a closer look
我们来详细了解一下
at one of the most popular categories of HomeKit accessories:
HomeKit 配件最普遍的分类之一
Lights.
灯
Millions of us have already added smart bulbs to our homes,
成千上万的人已经在家里安了智能灯泡
many of which can change color on demand.
很多灯泡能按照要求改变颜色
In iOS 14,
在 iOS 14 里
we're introducing a feature to help you get the most out of those bulbs:
我们要引入一个功能来帮助大家 充分利用这些灯泡
Adaptive lighting.
自适应光线调节
Adaptive lighting automatically adjusts the color temperature of your lights
自适应光线调节能够全天自动调节
throughout the day.
灯光的颜色温度
Turn it on to ease into the morning with warm colors,
打开它 伴随着暖色进入清晨
stay focused and alert midday with cooler ones,
保持专注 色调转冷 提示人们中午到了
and wind down at night by reducing blue light.
晚上 通过减少蓝光 色调变缓和
Adaptive lighting ensures you get the right color at the right time.
自适应光线调节确保灯光能够在 合适的时间 变成合适的颜色
Another popular smart home category is cameras.
另一个很普遍的智能家居分类是摄像头
With HomeKit Secure Video your cameras are completely private.
有 HomeKit 安防视频 你的摄像头完全是私秘的
And in iOS 14, we're making your cameras work even harder for you.
在 iOS 14 里 我们让你的摄像头 更加努力地为你工作
You'll be able to define Activity Zones that focus on the most important areas.
你将能够规定专门拍摄 最重要的活动区域
This is great if you face a busy sidewalk
如果你家门前行人较多
and only want to be alerted when people actually walk up to your front door.
而你只想在有人走到你家前门时被提醒 这个功能是很棒的
Another powerful feature we're bringing to cameras is face recognition.
我们要给摄像头添加的另一个强大功能 就是面孔识别功能
HomeKit cameras and video doorbells will now provide even richer notifications,
HomeKit 的摄像头和视频门铃 将提供更丰富的通知
telling you who's there by leveraging the friends and family
充分利用你 照片 app 里 你给朋友和家人添加的标签
you've already tagged in your Photos app.
告诉你谁来了
And face recognition extends to HomePod, announcing who's at the door.
And with Apple TV, you'll get a live view whenever someone rings the bell.
In fact, all your HomeKit-enabled cameras will be directly integrated with tvOS 14
so you can quickly bring them up in the new home view in Control Center.
这样你就能快速在控制中心的 新主视图调用它们了
Or just ask Siri to pull up any camera at any time.
或者直接随时让 Siri 开启任何摄像头
You can even take any camera full-screen,
你可以让摄像头开启全屏模式
giving you a great view of what's going on.
让你看清发生的一切
And we have even more coming to tvOS 14.
关于 tvOS 14 还有更多精彩内容
Now let me pass it to Cindy Lin to tell you about it.
让我们欢迎 Cindy Lin 来为大家讲解
Thanks, Yah.
谢谢 Yah
Apple TV is my favorite way to unwind and enjoy entertainment with the family.
With 4K, HDR,
有了 4K、HDR
Dolby Vision and Dolby Atmos,
杜比视界和杜比全景声
you get a theater-like experience right in your living room,
你能在你家客厅享受的影院式的体验
making all your movies and shows look and sound amazing.
让所有电影和节目的视觉 和音响效果超凡绝伦
But Apple TV goes beyond video.
但 Apple TV 不只是视频
You can access the entire Apple Music collection
你可以通过它去听 整个 Apple Music 专题
and even sing along with timed lyrics.
甚至跟着同步好的歌词一起唱
You can play an incredible selection of games,
你可以通过它玩各种好玩的游戏
including all the games in Apple Arcade.
包括 Apple Arcade 里的所有游戏
And we're making gaming on Apple TV even more personal
我们还可以通过扩展多用户支持
by expanding multiuser support.
让在 Apple TV 玩游戏变得更加个性化
Now you can instantly resume your games exactly where you left off.
现在你可以迅速让游戏 回到之前的保存进度
Just open Control Center to switch between users,
只需打开控制中心 在用户之间进行切换
and you can now see your game progress, achievements and friends.
你就能看到你的游戏进度、成就和好友
And for even more fun, we're adding support
为了增加趣味性 我们将添加对
for Xbox Elite 2 and Xbox Adaptive Controllers.
Xbox Elite 无线控制器 2 代和 Xbox Adaptive Controllers 的支持
Apple TV also helps you keep active at home
有大量可选的健身 app Apple TV 也会帮助大家
with a great selection of fitness apps.
在家也能保持运动
And with tvOS 14,
有了 tvOS 14
we're gonna make your workouts, and everything you do on Apple TV,
我们将让你的体能训练和 你在 Apple TV 所做的一切
even more productive by extending Picture in Picture
变得更富有成效 办法就是 在整个 Apple TV 体验中
across the entire Apple TV experience.
扩展画中画功能
So you can keep up with the news or not miss a second of the big game.
这样你就能跟进新闻 或者不错过一场重要比赛的任何一瞬间
You can even have an AirPlay session show up in a Picture in Picture window.
你甚至可以把隔空播放的会话 放到一个画中画窗口里播放
And AirPlay is getting even better.
隔空播放功能也会变得更好
Now the whole family can share their stunning videos captured on iPhone
现在全家人可以共享 iPhone 拍下的精彩视频
in their full 4K resolution.
分辨率高达 4K
With videos, music, games and more,
加上视频、音乐、游戏还有更多其他功能
Apple TV truly offers something for everyone.
Apple TV 真的给所有人提供了一些东西
Of course, nothing compares to being captivated by a good story.
当然 没什么能比得上 被一个好故事所吸引
And we've built a service for just that: Apple TV+.
我们专门为此创立了一个服务 Apple TV+
We've already created an incredible lineup of Apple Originals.
我们已经创建了一系列精彩的 Apple Originals 节目
And you can watch them all in the Apple TV app,
全部都能在 Apple TV app 上观看
which is available on your favorite Apple devices,
你可以在你喜爱的 Apple 设备
on all major streaming boxes
所有主流的流媒体播放器
and many popular smart TVs.
和诸多热门的智能电视上下载这个 app
It's already reaching over a billion screens.
这个 app 已经普及到 超过十亿个屏幕上了
And it's coming to Sony and Vizio smart TVs later this summer.
今年夏末 它也会在 Sony 和 Vizio 的智能电视上推出
Today, we're really excited to tell you about a new Apple TV+ Original
今天 我们很高兴地告诉大家 我们正在制作的
that we're working on.
一部新的 Apple TV+ Original 节目
Almost 70 years ago,
大约七十年前
Isaac Asimov introduced the world to a series of epic novels
Isaac Asimov 带给了世人 一系列史诗般的经典小说
that spanned hundreds of worlds and thousands of years.
小说里描写了成百上千个世界 时间跨度成千上万年
Many consider it to be the best science-fiction series of all time.
很多人认为它是有史以来 最棒的科幻系列作品
I'd like to share a sneak peek with you now.
我想现在分享一个片段 让大家先睹为快
This is Foundation.
这部杰作就是《Foundation》
[dramatic music playing]
They're going to arrest me tomorrow.
他们会在明天逮捕我
And you. It's almost a certainty.
还有你 这几乎没什么悬念
You're familiar with my work, psychohistory?
你熟悉我的工作 心理史学？
Yes, in theory. But I don't know what it has to do with--
理论上我熟悉 但我不知道它如何能和…
It's not a theory.
它不是理论
[Salvor] They're worried you can predict the future.
他们担心你能够预知未来
[whirring]
[Hari] They're worried people believe I can.
他们担心人们相信我能够做到
[whirring]
And they don't like the future I predict.
他们不喜欢我预知的未来
The empire will fall.
帝国将灭亡
Order will vanish.
秩序将消失
There's massive events rushing to meet us.
诸多重大事件正在迅速涌向我们
[Salvor] Only we can shorten the darkness.
[music fades]
Wow. I'm super excited to watch Foundation when it comes to Apple TV+ next year.
哇 明年就能在 Apple TV+ 上 观看 《Foundation》 太令人兴奋了
With Apple TV, your home has never been more entertaining.
有了 Apple TV 你就只想待在家里玩
And with adaptive lighting, face recognition for cameras
and these other great features,
和这些其它激动人心的功能
your time at home has never been more enjoyable.
你在家的时间会更加富有乐趣
Now let me hand it back to Craig.
现在将时间交给 Craig
Welcome back.
欢迎回来
Now let's talk about some big changes coming to macOS.
现在 让我们来看看 macOS 即将出现的重大变化
Since its introduction,
从它进入市场以来
macOS has revolutionized the experience of using a computer
macOS 革新了使用电脑的体验
by combining incredible power with incredible ease of use.
将令人难以置信的强大功能 和易用性结合在一起
And it's loved by all different types of users,
各种类型的用户都喜欢使用这种操作系统
from families and students
包括家庭用户和学生
to creative pros,
创作专业人士
businesspeople and, of course, software developers.
商务人士 当然还包括软件开发者
And this year, we're taking the macOS experience you love
今年 我们将让人们喜爱的 macOS
even further.
更上一层楼
But what should we call it?
但是我们应该怎么为它命名呢？
Well, if you're a student of macOS, you know this question
如果你对 macOS 颇有研究 那么你就会知道
can only be answered by Apple's legendary crack marketing team.
这个问题只有 Apple 公司 传奇的营销团队才能回答
Their drug-fueled, minibus-driven vision quests
他们充满激情的疯狂追寻
have yielded some great names
碰撞出很多伟大的名字
and, sadly, spawned a host of imitators.
不幸的是也出现了大量的模仿者
The truth is, we can't responsibly continue
实际上 我们不能再继续
to inadvertently lead our competition to copy these methods
不经意地任由我们的竞争对手 去效仿这些方法
when they clearly can't handle the trip.
因为他们明明承受不起
So this year, we're leaving our process shrouded in mystery
所以今年 我们将碰撞灵感的过程 笼罩在神秘之中
and taking you straight to the glorious destination.
直接将你们带向辉煌的目的地
Our next release of macOS is macOS Big Sur.
我们下一版本的 macOS 被称为 macOS Big Sur
macOS Big Sur introduces an entirely new design
macOS Big Sur 对平台上 一些基本的 app
and major updates to some of the most essential apps on the platform.
引入了全新的设计和一些重大更新
And just like its name,
就像它的名称一样
Big Sur brings you unmatched levels of power and beauty.
Big Sur 为你呈现 无与伦比的强大功能和美丽外观
Let's start with design,
我们首先看看它的设计
where we're making the biggest change since the introduction of Mac OS X.
这是自 Mac OS X 被推出以来 变化最为重大的一次
To tell you more about the philosophy and incredible craftsmanship
为了更详细地阐述新颖设计背后的哲学
behind the new design,
和难以置信的工艺技巧
here's a short video with Alan Dye.
请看看 Alan Dye 的短片
[piano playing]
At Apple, design has always been about great ideas.
Those ideas then are developed with this obsessive dedication to detail.
这些想法的开发过程 则又充满了对细节狂热的专注
If we care enough about all the details that make up a product,
如果我们对组成产品的各种细节足够关注
then in the end we will have designed an experience
那么最后我们设计出的这种体验 将使我们感觉到
that really feels like there's no other way it could be.
不可能有另外的方式能够实现
And the best example of this is macOS Big Sur.
最好的例子就是 macOS Big Sur
Our goal was to bring even more clarity to the design of the software
我们的目标是软件的设计更加清晰
while retaining the Mac's powerful capability and ease of use.
同时保持 Mac 强大的功能和易用性
We started with the simplest of elements,
我们从最简单的元素开始
from the shape of a corner radius to refinements in buttons and controls.
从圆角的半径到按钮和控件的改良
And we brought our unified language of symbols to the Mac,
我们将符号的统一语言引入了 Mac
making them more consistent and easier to recognize.
使其更加统一和易于识别
Depth, shading and translucency
使用深度 阴影和半透明
are used to create hierarchy.
来创建层级
These new materials are rich, and they're vibrant.
这些新材料非常丰富且充满生机
They bridge light and dark.
它们连接着明亮与黑暗
We've reduced visual complexity to keep the focus on users' content.
我们减少了视觉复杂性 以保持专注于用户内容
Buttons and controls appear when you need them,
当你需要时才会出现按钮和控件
and they recede when you don't.
当你不需要时便会隐藏
There's a new way to access system-level controls
访问系统级控件也有着全新的方式
and a unified space for notifications and widgets.
通知和小组件也有着统一的空间
We've also created a new suite of sounds.
我们还创建了一套新的声音
They're familiar to the Mac, but remastered and more refined.
都是 Mac 上熟悉的声音 但经过重制 使其更加动听
[pulses]
（Ivy 发送中…）
[alert notifications chiming]
We wanted consistency throughout the ecosystem,
我们想让整个生态系统具有一致性
so users can move fluidly between their Apple devices.
这样 用户就可以在 Apple 设备之间自由切换
But we also love that Mac icons have a deep history
但我们也喜欢 Mac 图标 有着深厚的历史印记
and a distinct look and feel.
以及独特的外观和感觉
So we've retained many of the highly crafted details
所以我们保留了许多精巧的细节
and the playful elements that make Mac icons unique.
和有趣的元素 使 Mac 图标保持独特性
This OS reflects an important history.
这种 OS 反映了重要的历史
It's familiar, but it's also entirely new in every detail.
它让人感觉熟悉 但每个细节又是全新的
We love the Mac.
我们喜爱 Mac
It's the tool we use to make all the products that we put out into the world.
它是我们的工具 用来创造走向世界的产品
And macOS Big Sur is where it starts.
macOS Big Sur 是个新的开始
[Craig] So that's the thinking behind our new design.
所以 那就是我们新设计背后的思考
Now let me show it to you in action with a demo.
现在我演示给你们看看实际操作
As Alan said,
正如 Alan 所说
we've refined some of the most iconic elements of the Mac experience.
我们对一些在 Mac 体验中 最具有标志性的元素做了改进
Let's start with the Dock.
我们先来看看程序坞
It has an elegant new design that floats along the bottom of your desktop.
它有着设计优雅的外观 在桌面的底部悬浮着
And you'll notice that we've created gorgeous new app icons
你会注意到我们为所有你喜欢的 app
for all of your favorite apps.
都创造了漂亮的新 app 图标
Speaking of apps, let's take a look at the Finder.
说到 app 我们来看看访达
You notice it has a gorgeous new top-to-bottom design for the sidebar,
你可以看到其在边栏 有着漂亮的整体新设计
and it has a compact, space-efficient toolbar.
外形紧凑 有效利用空间的工具栏
Makes it really easy to get to all of your controls.
使你更容易使用全部控件
Next, let's take a look at Mail.
然后 我们来看看邮件
You can see that Mail has all-new glyphs in the sidebar,
你可以看到邮件的边栏拥有了全新图标
and you may have noticed that we've brought color back as well.
你可能还注意到我们也把颜色加了回来
Now, each app uses its own key color.
现在 每种 app 都使用它们自己的基色
That same color is used for the elegant new rounded row selection style
相同的颜色也用于 优雅、饱满的行选风格
here in the message list.
这就是全新的邮件列表
Now, the toolbar makes it really easy to get to all your controls.
现在的工具栏使得 访问所有的控件更加容易
Check out how the search bar expands as I click on it.
看看当我点击搜索栏时它是如何展开的
And, of course, other operations like filtering,
当然 类似于过滤等其它操作
they're just a click away.
只需要点击一下即可
Next, let's take a look at Photos.
然后 我们来看看照片
It's just stunning.
它太令人震惊了
You can get to all your albums and media types from the sidebar,
你可以从边栏中 获取你的全部相册和媒体类型
and the photo grid is backed by Metal,
有 Metal 支持的照片格
so animations are super smooth
使动画非常平滑
whether I'm scrolling, transitioning
不管我是上下滚动、转换
or zooming all the way in or all the way out.
或是全面缩放
It's beautiful.
真的很美妙
Now we've refreshed the design for all the apps on the system,
我们现在更新了系统中所有 app 的设计
from apps like Calendar and Notes
从日历和备忘录
to Podcasts and Music, with its new Listen Now pane.
到播客 app 和使用 全新“Listen Now”面板的音乐 app
And an all-new version of iWork that features a simplified toolbar.
以及一个配有 简化工具栏的全新版 iWork
You may have noticed we've also updated the menu bar.
你可能注意到我们还更新了菜单栏
It's now translucent and elegantly takes on the color of your desktop picture.
它现在是半透明的 优雅地透着桌面图像的颜色
And we've updated the layout of menus as well.
我们还更新了菜单的布局
We've given all the items just a little bit more room to breathe.
让一切都不要那么紧凑
Now, on the Mac, we love our ability to get directly at controls,
在 Mac 上 我们喜欢能够直接操作控件的能力
like Wi-Fi or Sound.
例如 Wi-Fi 或声音
And you can see that we've reworked these to be even more useful.
你会发现我们对这些元素 重新进行了规划 使其更加有用
But we've gone even further this year
但是今年我们更进了一步
by giving you one place to get at all your controls.
使你能够在一个地方访问所有控件
We've brought Control Center to the Mac.
我们在 Mac 中引入了控制中心
All of my controls are here, and it's really easy to make adjustments.
我的所有控件都在那儿 并且非常容易进行调整
For instance, I can change display brightness here
例如 我可以在这里改变显示亮度
or I can click to dive in for more,
我也可以点击进行更深入的调试
like turning on Dark Mode or activating Night Shift.
比如开启深色模式 或启用夜览
And what's really cool is that I can customize the menu bar
真正神奇的是我能够使用这些控件
with any of these controls.
定制菜单栏
So, say I want one-click access to Do Not Disturb.
譬如 如果我想一键访问勿扰模式
I can just click and drag it right into my menu bar
我只需点击并将其拖动到我的菜单栏
and customize just like that.
这样就自定义好了
Now we've also reinvented Notification Center.
我们也重建了通知中心
You can access it by clicking on the time in the upper right.
你可以点击右上方的时间来访问它
And as you see, we now have a single view
如你所见 我们现在由同一个视图
that brings your notifications and widgets together all in one place.
来显示通知和小组件
And we now group related notifications together.
我们现在将相关通知归纳在一起
You can easily expand them to take a closer look
你能够方便地展开它们 以便进一步对其进行查看
or clear them all out in one step.
或者一步全部清除
And we're bringing our redesigned widgets to the Mac.
我们还为 Mac 带来了重新设计的小组件
They're really beautiful.
它们真的非常漂亮
And you have all-new ways to customize them.
你能够以全新的方式对其进行自定义
I'm just gonna click "Edit Widgets" down here at the bottom.
我只需要点击位于底部的“Edit Widgets”
And you can see I have a gallery of all my widgets,
你就可以看见我有一整套的小组件
and they come in a variety of sizes.
而且它们大小不一
I can select between them just like this.
我可以像这样在它们之间选择
And developers can bring their own widgets as well,
开发者还可以纳入他们自己的小组件
like this one here from Day One.
就像这个来至自 Day One 的小组件一样
Now adding widgets is easy.
现在添加小组件非常简单
Let's start by adding, say, the World Clock.
让我们从添加世界时钟开始
Maybe I'll add Notes in.
我可能还要添加备忘录
And it'd be kind of cool to add my Reminders list as well.
添加我的提醒事项列表也很酷
So that's a look at Widgets, Notification Center
我们已经对 Big Sur 中的 小组件、通知中心
and our all-new design in Big Sur.
和我们全新设计进行了简要说明
Next, there are exciting updates for some of the most-used apps on the Mac.
下面我们来看看 Mac 上 一些常用 app 的激动人心的更新
First, let's talk about Messages.
首先 我们来看看信息
Messages on the Mac is designed to work seamlessly with all of your devices,
Mac 的信息设计旨在 让你在所有的设备上实现无缝同步
so your SMS and iMessage conversations are in sync
所以不管你用的是哪一个设备
no matter what device you're using.
你的 SMS 和 iMessage 信息对话 都能得到同步
Now this year we're taking Messages to the next level
今年我们将信息提升到了更高的层次
with a ton of great new features.
加入了大量让人心动的新功能
We're introducing powerful search to help you find what you're looking for.
我们引入了强大的搜索功能 帮助你寻找想要找的内容
We have a redesigned photo picker to make sharing photos and videos easier.
我们重新设计了照片挑选器 使你更方便地分享照片和视频
And Memoji. You can now create and edit your Memoji right on your Mac.
还有拟我表情 你现在能在 Mac 上创建并编辑拟我表情
And Memoji stickers bring personality to messages,
拟我表情贴纸给信息增添了个性
giving you fun ways to express yourself in all of your conversations.
使你在所有的聊天对话中 能够以有趣的方式表达自己
Messages effects helps you celebrate special moments
信息特效有助于你庆祝特别的时刻
and get your point across.
还有助于传达你的观点
And you're also getting pinned conversations
你还可以将聊天置顶
that are synced across devices so you can always get to them,
聊天内容会在不同设备之间同步 这样你永远可以找到它们
along with new Groups enhancements.
再加上新的群组增强功能
So that's what's coming to Messages on Mac:
这就是 Mac 上信息的新特性
powerful tools to manage your conversations
管理聊天对话的强大工具
and new ways to express yourself.
和表达自我的新方式
Next up, Maps.
下面我们谈谈地图
Apple Maps is the best way to explore and navigate the world,
Apple 地图是探索和遨游世界的最佳方式
whether you're planning a trip on the Mac
不管你是在 Mac 上规划旅行
or using turn-by-turn directions on your iPhone.
还是在 iPhone 上使用逐向导航功能
Today I'm excited to announce an all-new version of Maps for the Mac.
今天我非常高兴地宣布 Mac 采用了一种全新版本的地图
To start, Maps features a stunning new design
首先 地图有着绝佳的新设计
that makes it easy to find your way around using Apple's detailed new map.
能够让你使用 Apple 详细的新地图 来找到自己的路线
And for the first time on the Mac,
而且作为在 Mac 上首次出现的功能
Favorites like home, work or that great coffee shop on the corner
现在只需点击一下就可以去到 收藏列表里储存的地点，比如家、工作
are now just a click away.
或者是街角那家很棒的咖啡厅
You can now create your own Guides of all the places you want to visit
你现在可以在 Mac 上 为你想去的所有地方
right on your Mac.
创建你自己的指南
And before leaving for the airport,
在去机场之前
you can check where your gate is located with indoor maps
你可以在室内地图上 查看你登机口的所在位置
or explore your destination city with Look Around,
或使用四处看看探索目的地城市
which is incredible on the big screen.
此功能在大屏幕上效果极好
We've even brought other useful features to the Mac,
我们还在 Mac 中加入了其它有用的功能
like the ability to see the progress of friends
例如那些和你共享预计达到时间的朋友
who have shared their ETA with you.
我们可以查看他们具体的位置
And the Mac gets all the other new Maps features
Mac 具有我们刚在 iOS 14 中引入的
we just introduced in iOS 14.
所有其他新地图的功能
And that's just a taste of what's coming in the all-new Apple Maps on the Mac.
以上就是对 Mac 上全新 Apple 地图的 简单介绍
Next let's talk about Mac Catalyst.
下面我们来谈谈 Mac Catalyst
Catalyst gives developers a big head start
Catalyst 为开发者提供了 一个良好的开端
in creating a Mac app from an iPad app.
让它们可以从 iPad app 中创建 Mac app
Take, for instance, our recent release of Swift Playgrounds for Mac.
以我们最近发布的 Mac 版本的 Swift Playgrounds 为例
Catalyst gave us a big head start creating the app,
Catalyst 使我们在创建 这个 app 时领先一步
and we were able to spend our development time
我们能够将我们的开发时间
crafting a great Mac experience.
用于构建良好的 Mac 体验上
Today we have some improvements to Mac Catalyst I'd like to share.
今天 我想要分享一些 和 Mac Catalyst 有关的新改进
This year, developers will be able to optimize their apps
今年 开发者将能够优化他们的 apps
to fully utilize the native resolution of the Mac screen,
以便充分使用 Mac 屏幕的原始分辨率
providing total control of every pixel.
完全控制每个像素
We've also given developers new capabilities,
我们还为开发者提供了新功能
including powerful new menu and keyboard APIs
包括强大的新菜单和键盘 API
and updated controls like checkboxes and date pickers.
以及复选框和日期选择器等更新的控件
They look great with the new design of macOS.
在 macOS 新设计下 它们看起来非常棒
In fact, we used Catalyst with the new version of Maps.
事实上 我们的新版本地图 使用了 Catalyst
And just as you'd expect,
正如你们的想一样
it's a full-fledged Mac app that runs natively
它在本机运行 是一个完全成熟的 Mac app
and is designed in a way that's true to the Mac.
其设计完全符合 Mac 的运行方式
So you get multiple resizable windows, keyboard shortcuts
所以你拥有 多个可调整尺寸的窗口、键盘快捷键
and everything else you'd expect from a native Mac app.
以及原生 Mac app 应该拥有的其它所有功能
And we did the same thing for Messages.
我们对信息也进行了相同的更新
Maps and Messages join the great set of apps from Apple
地图和信息都成为了使用 Mac Catalyst 技术的
that already use the Mac Catalyst technology.
一系列 Apple app 中一份子
And there's a growing list of third-party Catalyst apps available
在 Mac App Store 中
on the Mac App Store.
使用 Catalyst 技术的 app 越来越多
Next... Safari.
下面…谈谈 Safari 浏览器
Our users love Safari
用户喜欢 Safari 浏览器
for its speedy performance, power efficiency
喜欢其快速的性能、高能效
and state-of-the-art privacy protections.
和最先进的隐私保护
And it delivers all of that
在具备这些特性的同时
while making it easy to get to your bookmarks, tabs and browsing history
它还能让你在各种设备之间
across all of your devices.
轻松访问书签、标签页和浏览历史
This year, we're building on Safari's amazing performance,
我们今年基于 Safari 浏览器 令人惊异的性能
elegant design and pioneering privacy protections
高雅的设计和开创性的隐私保护
to deliver the biggest update to Safari since it was first introduced.
给用户带来自 Safari 浏览器推出以来 最重大的一次更新
As you know, Safari has long been the world's fastest desktop browser.
如你所知 Safari 浏览器长期以来 一直是世界上最快的桌面浏览器
This year, Safari's performance running JavaScript is better than ever
今年 Safari 浏览器运行 JavaScript 的性能比以前要好很多
and continues to significantly outpace all other major browsers.
并继续遥遥领先于所有其它主要的浏览器
And now, when it comes to page loading, we're even faster there too.
现在 在进行页面加载时 我们的速度也快得多
In fact, when loading frequently visited websites,
事实上 在加载经常访问的网站时
Safari is now on average more than 50% faster than Chrome.
现在 Safari 浏览器 平均比 Chrome 快50%以上
And Safari delivers this amazing performance
Safari 浏览器 在提供这种优异性能的同时
while continuing to deliver industry-leading battery life.
还继续保持行业领先的电池续航时间
And of course, Safari is continuing to build
当然 Safari 浏览器仍在不断努力
on its pioneering track record of protecting user privacy.
巩固其在用户隐私保护方面的领先地位
Safari was the first browser to introduce private browsing, cookie blocking,
Safari 浏览器是引入无痕浏览 阻止 Cookie 的第一款浏览器
and most recently, Intelligent Tracking Prevention.
最近还引入了智能防跟踪功能
This year, we want to give our users even more visibility
今年 我们希望给用户更多透明度
into how each site they visit tries to track them
让他们了解 访问的每个网站是如何追踪他们的
and the ways that Safari protects them.
以及 Safari 浏览器是如何保护他们的
So now users can click on the Privacy Report button in the toolbar
现在用户可以点击 工具条里的“隐私报告”按钮
when they visit a site
使他们在访问网站时
to better understand how that site is treating their privacy.
更好地了解网站如何处理他们的隐私
In addition to monitoring unwanted tracking,
除了监控不受欢迎的追踪
Safari now also securely monitors your saved passwords
Safari 浏览器还能够 安全地监控你保存的密码
to ensure that they haven't been compromised in a data breach.
保证它们在数据泄露时不会被连累
And this is also a big year for extensions in Safari.
对于 Safari 浏览器扩展 今年也是非常重要的一年
We're adding support for the WebExtensions API
我们添加了 WebExtensions API 的支持
so developers can easily bring over extensions
所以开发者能够轻松地 将他们给其它浏览器
that they built for other browsers.
构建的扩展移植过来
And we're building an all-new category in the Mac App Store
我们正在 Mac App Store 中 构建一个全新的类别
to showcase Safari extensions so users can easily find them.
以展示 Safari 浏览器扩展 从而方便用户找到它们
Now extensions are very powerful
现在，扩展非常强大
but can introduce privacy challenges.
但是可能会导致隐私问题
In other browsers, extensions can access every page you visit,
在其它浏览器中 扩展可以访问你浏览的每个页面
every tab you open,
你打开的每个标签页
even everything you type.
甚至是你输入的每个字符
So we're doing even more here.
所以我们在这些方面做了更多工作
In Safari, you choose which sites each extension can work with,
在 Safari 浏览器中 你来选择每个扩展可访问的网站
and you can even give them access just for the day,
你甚至可以授权扩展只在当天访问
just for the website or all the time.
或仅访问该网站 或者随时访问
But improved performance,
但是更强的性能
power efficiency and privacy protections are only the start.
能效和隐私保护仅仅是开始而已
We have a whole slew of new features this year.
我们今年还要引入大量的新功能
From a customizable start page
包括可自定义的起始页
to redesigned tabs that are more elegant and powerful,
重新设计的更加美观和强大的标签页
and native translation capabilities built right into Safari.
以及 Safari 浏览器内置的翻译功能
To tell you more, I'll hand it off to Beth Dakin.
更多内容 我将交给 Beth Dakin 来讲解
Thanks, Craig.
I'm so excited to give you a tour of the brand-new Safari.
When you open Safari, right away you'll notice the new look.
当你打开 Safari 浏览器时 马上就会注意到它的新外观
It's clean and fresh.
简洁而清爽
I want to show you one of my favorite new features:
我想给大家展示我最爱的新功能之一
the customizable start page.
自定义起始始页
I love it because I can make it my own.
我超爱此功能 我可以把它变成自己的风格
It's easy to get to the customization controls
在右下角即可轻松打开
here in the bottom corner.
自定义控件
We think a lot of people are gonna want to set a background image,
我们猜很多人应该想要设置背景图
and there's a beautiful gallery of curated wallpapers to choose from.
这有许多精心挑选的壁纸可供选择
You can use one of your own photos, too, and I know I want a photo of my son.
你也可以用自己的图片 我想要用我儿子的照片
I have a few really cute ones here in the downloads.
在下载文件夹里 有几张我儿子特别可爱的照片
I can just drag and drop to set it.
我只要将照片拖放进来 即可设置好
That is so perfect.
太完美了
You can add new sections to the start page too.
你可以在起始页添加新的部分
Let's add iCloud Tabs and Reading List.
让我们来添加 iCloud 标签页和阅读列表
Let's take a look.
来看一下
There. This is perfect.
看 完美
I use Reading List all the time, and now it's so easy to get to.
我经常用阅读列表 现在更加容易打开了
Another way that you can dial in Safari to suit your specific needs
还有一种方法可以让 Safari 浏览器 更加符合个性化需求
is with extensions.
就是使用扩展
I can't wait for you developers to bring your web extensions to Safari.
我非常期待看到开发者们 能够将自己的扩展带到 Safari 浏览器
I've gone ahead and downloaded a few web extensions to take a peek.
我提前下载了几个网页扩展来一睹为快
So let's go here to the Safari preferences to enable them.
打开 Safari 浏览器使用偏好 启用扩展
And I'll enable Power Thesaurus and Recipe Filter.
启用 Power Thesaurus 和 Recipe Filter
So each of the extensions that I just enabled
我刚刚启用的这两个扩展
now has its own button here in the toolbar.
现在在工具栏上有了自己的按钮
Let me show you Recipe Filter. I love this one.
我给大家看看 Recipe Filter 我超爱这个
So this extension will search the web page for a recipe,
这个扩展会搜索当前网页上的菜谱
and if it finds one, it will pop it up in a little card.
如果找到了就会弹出一个小卡片
It's been a great accelerator for me when I'm building a grocery list.
当我在列食材清单的时候 这个扩展为我省了不少事
So the extension hasn't done anything yet because I haven't granted permission.
因为我还没有给它权限 所以这个扩展现在还没有启动
So let me click on the toolbar button,
让我点一下工具栏上的按钮
and I'm going to allow this extension for one day.
然后给这个扩展一天的权限
And when I click here, it'll do its thing.
当我点击这里 这个扩展就运行了
So here we go. And there it is. So useful.
你看 这就出来了 非常好用
Okay, so I have my personality
目前 我的 Safari 浏览器
pretty thoroughly stamped over Safari at this point.
已经高度贴合我的个性了
And you know, I use Safari for a lot of personal things,
如各位所见 我用 Safari 浏览器做很多私人的事情
and Apple makes sure my private life stays private.
Apple 保证了我的私人隐私不被侵犯
Privacy is essential to everything we do at Apple, and it's critical on the web.
在 Apple 隐私是我们所有工作的基础 在网上更是关键
And now you can see what Safari is doing to protect you.
现在 你可以看到 Safari 浏览器 是如何保护你的隐私的
If I click on the Intelligent Tracking Prevention button,
如果我点击这个智能防跟踪功能按钮
I can see the number of known trackers
我可以看到网页上已知的跟踪器数量
that Safari protected me from on this web page.
Safari 浏览器保护我的隐私不受其侵犯
I can click here
我可以点击这里
to see a list of the known trackers right here in this popover.
在这个弹出框里 看所有已知追踪器的清单
And the full privacy report is just one click away.
只需轻点一下 就能看到完整的隐私报告
And that's what we have for privacy in the new Safari.
这就是新的 Safari 浏览器里隐私的功能
Next I'd like to talk about tabs.
接下来 我想跟大家聊一聊标签页
If you love tabs, you're going to love the new Safari.
如果你喜欢标签页 那你一定会爱上新的 Safari 浏览器
It's easier and more efficient than ever to work with lots of tabs.
在同时开启很多标签页的情况下 Safari 浏览器变得更加简单和高效
So I have another window here,
我还打开了另一个窗口
and right away you'll notice that there are icons and tabs,
大家马上可以发现 这里有很多图标和标签页
which makes it so easy to spot what you're looking for.
这样一来 找东西就快多了
And if I open more tabs, then you'll see more of them at once
如果我打开更多标签页 所有标签页都出现在这个窗口上
because the tabs get smaller and use the space more efficiently.
因为标签页变小了 空间的使用率提高了
If it's a little hard to find what you're looking for with this many tabs,
在打开了这么多标签页的情况下 想要找到自己想要的网页有点困难的话
that's no problem.
完全不是问题
You can just hover over tabs and see a nice preview of the page.
你可以将鼠标指针停在标签页上 就会出现这个网页的预览
I'm ready to clean up now, and that's easy too.
我现在可以关掉了 关标签页也很简单
I can just bring up the context menu here
我可以打开环境菜单
and close all tabs to the right. Just like that.
把当前标签页右边的所有标签页都关掉 就这么简单
We are so excited that the new Safari has built-in translation.
我们非常激动 新的 Safari 浏览器有了内置翻译功能
Let me show you.
我来为大家演示一下
So here on this website, on El Mundo,
在《世界报》网站上
Safari has detected that this is not in my primary language,
Safari 浏览器检测到了 这不是我的主要语言
and it's added the translation icon to the smart search field.
所以在智能搜索框里 Safari 浏览器加上了翻译图标
I can click here, and let's translate this page to English.
我点击这里 就能把这个网页翻成英文
It'll happen inline.
翻译文本会直接替换
And as more content is added,
当下滑显示更多内容时
that gets translated dynamically too.
也会实时动态进行翻译
Those are some highlights, but there is so much more to the new Safari.
除了这些重点功能 新 Safari 浏览器还有更多功能待你发掘
Back to you, Craig.
把画面交还给 Craig
Thanks, Beth.
谢谢你 Beth
So that's Safari.
这就是 Safari 浏览器的介绍
It's a huge release, with new ways to customize,
这是一个重量级发布 带来了全新的自定义方式
big improvements to your browsing experience
能够大大改善浏览体验
like tabs and translation,
像是标签页和翻译功能等等
and even stronger privacy protection
还有更加强大的隐私保护机制
to keep your browsing your business.
让你的浏览只属于你自己
And that's macOS Big Sur,
这就是 macOS Big Sur
the biggest update to design since the original introduction of Mac OS X,
这是自 Mac OS X 问世以来 对设计最为大刀阔斧的升级
significant updates to Messages and Maps
信息和地图功能也有重大革新
and the biggest update to Safari ever.
而 Safari 浏览器更是迎来了 有史以来最大规模的更新
But these changes are only the beginning.
但这些变化仅仅是开始
For years now, down deep, below the surface,
多年以来 在深度保密的情况下
we've been working on something truly profound.
我们一直都在钻研一些更深层次的东西
To tell you more, I'll hand it back to Tim.
为了让大家了解更多 我现在把画面交回给 Tim
Thanks, Craig.
谢谢 Craig
Big Sur is going to be a great release of macOS.
Big Sur 将会成为 macOS 的重大发布
But that's only part of the story,
但这并不是全部
because today is going to be a truly historic day for the Mac.
因为今天将会是 Mac 产品线真正 具有历史意义的一天
Today we're going to tell you about some really big changes,
今天我们会向大家 介绍一些非常重大的变革
how we're going to take the Mac to a whole new level.
展示我们将如何 把 Mac 带到一个全新的阶段
From the very beginning,
从一开始
the Mac redefined the entire computer industry.
Mac 就重新定义了整个电脑行业
The Mac has always been about innovation and boldly pushing things forward,
一直以来 Mac 都是勇于创新 大胆推进新技术
embracing big changes to stay at the forefront of personal computing.
拥抱变革以站在个人电脑行业的最前端
The Mac has had three major transitions in its history.
Mac 共经历过三次重大变革
The move to PowerPC,
从最初的架构转变为 PowerPC 芯片
the transition to Mac OS X
再转换到 Mac OS X 操作系统
and the move to Intel.
然后迁移到 Intel 芯片
And now it's time for a huge leap forward for the Mac,
现在 Mac 又该向前大步跃进了
because today is the day we're announcing that the Mac is transitioning...
因为今天我们要宣布 Mac 将转换到…
to our own Apple Silicon.
我们自己的 Apple 芯片
When we make bold changes, it's for one simple yet powerful reason:
我们之所以要做出大胆的革新 只为了一个简单却有力的原因
so we can make much better products.
为了做出更好的产品
When we look ahead, we envision some amazing new products,
我们在展望未来时 会构思让人眼前一亮的新产品
and transitioning to our own custom silicon
而转换到我们自己的定制芯片
is what will enable us to bring them to life.
则能够让我们将这些构想付诸现实
At Apple,
integrating hardware and software is fundamental to everything we do.
That's what makes our products so great.
这是我们产品出众的根本原因
And silicon is at the heart of our hardware.
而芯片则是硬件的核心
So having a world-class silicon design team
所以拥有一个世界一流的芯片设计团队
is a game changer.
是带来变革的关键
To tell you more about Apple Silicon
为了让大家更进一步了解 Apple 芯片
and how it will take Mac to the next level,
以及它将如何带领 Mac 迈上新的高度
I'd like to send you over to Johny Srouji
有请 Johny Srouji
at one of our labs in an undisclosed location.
在我们一处位置保密的实验室 为大家带来介绍
["I'm Getting Tired" by Jacknife Lee playing]
[song ends]
Welcome to our lab.
欢迎大家来到我们的实验室
We've been building and refining our Apple Silicon for over a decade.
我们花了十几年的时间 来创造和优化 Apple 芯片
The result is a scalable architecture
最终带来了一个可扩展架构
that is custom-designed for Apple products,
专为 Apple 产品定制的芯片
and it leads the industry in features and performance per watt.
在特性和性能功耗比上实现了业界领先
So I'd like to tell you how we got here
下面为大家介绍一下开发历程
and what it means for the Mac moving forward.
以及它对 Mac 未来发展的意义
It all started with the iPhone.
一切始于 iPhone
The iPhone demanded performance and capabilities
iPhone 所需的性能和能力
that were seen as impossible in a device that small.
要在那么小的一个设备上实现 当时看几乎是不可能的
This is where we developed our relentless focus on performance per watt.
于是我们将重中之重放在了性能功耗比上
Generation after generation, we pushed the boundaries of technology,
一代又一代 我们不断进行着科技突破
which enabled us to improve performance and energy efficiency,
从而让我们能够改善性能和能耗效率
while building advanced and industry-leading features.
并开发出行业领先的高级功能
Our team delivered ten generations of increasingly complex and rich designs,
我们的团队已经带来了十代的产品 每一代的设计都更加复杂和丰富
always improving performance.
性能不断得到改善
In fact, CPU performance in the iPhone
实际上 iPhone 中 CPU 的性能
has improved by over a hundred times,
已经提高了超过100倍
keeping the iPhone's performance ahead of every other phone in the industry.
让 iPhone 的性能保持在业界榜首
Another opportunity for the team was the iPad.
团队遇到的另一个机遇则是 iPad
While iPhone chips could drive our mainstream iPads,
虽然 iPhone 的芯片能够驱动主流 iPad
we wanted to push the iPad even further.
我们还是想让 iPad 更进一步
It began with the iPad's Retina display,
一开始是因为 iPad 的视网膜显示屏
which demanded a custom chip.
需要一个定制芯片
So the team scaled our architecture
所以团队扩展了我们的架构
and designed the most-optimized
进而为 iPad 设计出了最为优化
and highest-performance chip possible for the iPad.
以及最高性能的芯片
Starting with the A5X,
从 A5X 开始
we built a line of SoCs specifically designed for the iPad.
我们打造了一系列 专为 iPad 设计的系统芯片
We doubled the iPhone's graphics performance through a larger GPU
我们通过更大的图形处理器 和更宽的存储器子系统
and a wider memory subsystem.
将 iPhone 的图形性能提高了一倍
This put the iPad in a class by itself.
这使得 iPad 本身独具一格
Compared to the very first iPad, the latest iPad Pro delivers
最新推出的 iPad Pro 的图形性能
over 1,000 times faster graphics performance
比第一代 iPad 快了一千倍
in just ten years.
这样的变化只用了十年时间
This is part of the reason why the iPad Pro is faster
这也是 iPad Pro 比大多数 PC 笔记本电脑
than the vast majority of PC laptops.
都要快的原因之一
And this foreshadows how well our architecture will scale into the Mac.
这也预示着 将这一架构扩展至 Mac 当中 也会创造非凡效果
Another place where we applied our focus was the Watch.
我们的另外一个重点领域是 Watch
We scaled our SoC architecture to optimize performance
我们扩展了系统芯片架构来优化性能
for the device's unique low-power requirements,
以满足设备独特的低能耗需求
and we built a chip perfectly suited for Apple Watch.
我们为 Apple Watch 打造了完美适配的芯片
Our SoCs enable each of these products with unique features
在我们系统芯片的帮助下 这些产品拥有独特的功能
and industry-leading performance per watt,
且性能功耗比在业界遥遥领先
and it makes each of them best in class.
使得它们成为同类产品中的佼佼者
And we do this at an enormous scale.
我们对系统芯片的应用非常广泛
In fact, adding all of the processors across these three products,
事实上 把这三款产品 所使用的处理器加在一起
we've shipped over two billion in just ten years.
我们在短短十年间 便交付了二十亿个系统芯片
And we've designed and shipped billions of additional chips
我们还设计并交付了数十亿其他芯片
that work together with our SoCs
这些芯片与系统芯片一道
to enable our amazing products.
让我们的产品卓尔不凡
And now we're bringing all of that expertise
而现在我们将这一专业技术
and that same focused and disciplined approach
以及同样的专注有序的方法
to the Mac.
应用在了 Mac 上
The first thing this will do is give the Mac a whole new level of performance.
这一做法首先 能够将 Mac 的性能推上崭新的台阶
Now, when we talk about performance, we have to talk about power,
当谈及性能时 一个不得不提的话题就是能耗
because all systems built today are constrained by power consumption,
因为当今所有的系统均受到能耗、散热
thermals, or both.
或者两者同时制约
Among today's consumer systems,
desktops deliver the highest performance
台式电脑的性能最强大
but consume the most power.
但能耗也最高
Notebooks trade off performance for lower power,
笔记本电脑则牺牲性能以换取更少的能耗
making them portable.
以达到便携的目的
As you can see, normally to get more performance
如大家所见 通常若想提高性能
you have to consume more power.
能耗必然增大
When you take a closer look at this chart,
若仔细看一下这个图表
you realize you want to operate in the upper-left corner.
会发现最理想的是 让产品落在左上这一区域
You want to deliver the highest performance
既要得到最高性能
at the lowest power consumption.
又要最低能耗
And that's exactly where we want to take the Mac.
而这就是我们对 Mac 的规划
Building up on our years of experience
基于我们多年
designing the world's most energy-efficient chips,
设计全球最节能芯片的经验
our plan is to give the Mac a much higher level of performance
我们的计划是大幅提高 Mac 的性能
while at the same time consuming less power.
与此同时减少能耗
So, much better performance is reason enough
因此 大幅提升性能这一个理由
to transition the Mac to Apple SoCs.
就足以让我们 把 Mac 换上 Apple 系统芯片 (SoC)
But that's just part of the story.
但这并不是全部
Our scalable architecture includes many custom technologies
我们的可扩展架构包含多项定制技术
that when integrated with our software
当这些技术与我们的软件整合在一起时
will bring even more innovation to the Mac.
会为 Mac 带来更大的创新
With our advanced power management,
在先进的电源管理系统帮助下
we will maximize performance and battery life
我们将最大化性能与电池续航时间
better than ever before.
比之前更好、更强大
Our Secure Enclave will bring best-in-class security,
与同类产品相比 我们的安全隔区将实现最大的安全性
and our high-performance GPU
我们的高性能图形处理器
is going to bring a whole new level of graphics performance to every Mac,
将为每一台 Mac 带来 更上一层楼的图形性能
making them even better for Pro Applications
使它们在专业应用方面更给力
and really great for games.
且在游戏方面的表现更突出
And combined with our neural engines,
芯片与神经网络引擎的结合
our chips will make the Mac an amazing platform for machine learning.
使得 Mac 的机器学习表现更优秀
And we're bringing many other custom technologies,
同样我们还带来了很多其他的定制技术
such as our video-display and image-processing engines,
比如视频显示与图形处理引擎
that will help make the Mac better than ever before.
将 Mac 推上崭新的台阶
So, what does all of this mean for the Mac?
那么这些对 Mac 来说意味着什么呢？
First, we're designing a family of SoCs specifically for the Mac product line.
首先 我们正在设计针对 Mac 产品线的 一系列系统芯片
Second, just like we did with the iPhone, iPad and Watch,
其次 如同 iPhone、iPad 和 Watch 一样
we're going to bring great technologies to the Mac.
我们也会将卓越的技术应用在 Mac 上
This will give the Mac a unique set of features
这会给 Mac 带来一系列独特的功能
and incredible performance.
以及无与伦比的性能表现
And third, we'll have a common architecture
第三点 我们这种共同架构
across all of our product lines,
遍布全部产品线
making it far easier for developers to write and optimize software
大大方便了开发者用优化后的软件
for the entire Apple ecosystem.
为整个 Apple 生态系统编写程序
Ultimately we know that bringing our SoCs to the Mac
最终 我们都知道 把我们的 系统芯片应用在 Mac 上
will allow us to build much better products,
会有助于我们做出更为出色的产品
and the Mac will take another huge leap forward.
Mac 则会再次取得巨大飞跃
Now, a key advantage we have
目前我们拥有的一个关键优势是
is the tight integration of our silicon with our software.
我们的芯片和软件的紧密集成
To tell you more about how macOS will run on Apple SoCs,
macOS 如何在 Apple 系统芯片上运行的详情
here is my colleague, Craig.
有请我的同事 Craig 来讲
Thanks, Johny.
谢谢 Johny
Now let's talk about the technologies that we've built into macOS Big Sur
现在我们来看一下 我们在 macOS Big Sur 上
that will make the transition to Apple Silicon smooth and seamless
内置了哪些技术可以确保用户和开发者 都能无缝顺畅地
for both consumers and developers.
过渡到使用 Apple 芯片
These new Mac systems will be incredible,
这些最新的 Mac 系统妙不可言
and users will want their favorite apps
用户肯定会希望自己最喜欢的 app
to take full advantage of the capabilities of our custom silicon.
充分利用上我们定制芯片的强大性能
And the best way to do that is with native apps.
而实现这个效果的最好方式就是 使用原生 app
So of course when we updated our apps for Big Sur,
所以 我们在为 Big Sur 更新我们自己的 app 时
we built everything as native for Apple Silicon.
当然就把这些 app 都打造成了适配 Apple 芯片的原生 app
And I'm happy to say we have all of our own Apple apps,
我在这里可以很高兴地说 我们所有的 Apple apps
including our most demanding Pro Apps like Final Cut Pro and Logic Pro,
包括对系统要求最高的专业应用 比如 Final Cut Pro 和 Logic Pro
up and running as native now,
现在作为原生 app 运行都非常顺畅
and they'll be ready for customers on day one.
消费者在新系统上线的第一天 就可以用上这些原生 app
So, how did we do this?
那我们是怎么做到的呢？
We're using Xcode, just like all our developers will.
我们用了 Xcode 和我们所有开发者的做法如出一辙
Everything developers need to build apps for these new chips
开发者在为这种新芯片开发 app 时 需要用到的一切
is built into the new version of Xcode.
都已内置到了新版 Xcode 中
To get started, developers just open their app projects and recompile.
开发者一开始只需打开自己的 app 项目 然后重新编译
The vast majority of developers can get their apps up and running
通过这种方式 绝大多数开发者只需要花几天时间
in just a matter of days.
就可以使自己的 app 在新系统上运行
And to deliver these apps,
为了开发出这些 app
we've created Universal 2.
我们创建了 Universal 2
It's a new type of Universal binary
这是一种新型 Universal 二进制程序代码
that works on both Intel-based Macs and Macs built on Apple Silicon.
既可以在装有 Intel 芯片的 Mac 上运行 也能在装有 Apple 芯片的 Mac 上用
So developers can tap into the native power and performance of our new Macs
所以开发者可以使用 新 Mac 的原生性能运行自己的 app
and still support Intel-based Macs,
同时，依然支持 基于 Intel 芯片的 Mac
all with a single binary for all of their users.
对他们的所有用户都使用 同一套二进制代码
Some of the biggest Mac developers have already gotten started.
在那些最大的 Mac 开发者中 有些已经开始付诸行动了
Microsoft is hard at work on Office for the Mac.
Microsoft 在努力优化 Mac 版 Office 软件
And we've been working with Adobe
而且我们一直在与 Adobe 合作
on their flagship Creative Cloud,
优化其旗舰产品 Creative Cloud 创意应用软件
and many of their apps are already up and running great.
而且他们的很多 app 已经可以非常顺畅地运行了
So let's take a look at macOS running on Apple Silicon.
那我们来看一下 macOS 在 Apple 芯片支持下的运行情况吧
So here we are on the desktop that we know and love.
我们现在看到的是大家熟知和钟爱的桌面
And I'm just gonna open up About This Mac.
我现在打开“关于本机”
And what you see here is that we are running on our Apple Development Platform.
大家现在看到的是 我们正在 Apple Development Platform 上运行
This is a system built to support early development
开发这个系统的目的是 为了支持早期开发
using the same A12Z processor
它用的是 A12Z 处理器
currently shipping in iPad Pro.
也是目前 iPad Pro 使用的芯片
Now, I have a confession to make.
现在我要和大家坦白一件事
This isn't the first time you've seen macOS running here.
这不是大家第一次看见 macOS 在这套系统运行了
In fact, this is the same Mac
其实这台 Mac 就是之前我和 Beth
that Beth and I used to demo all the new Big Sur features earlier.
用来演示 Big Sur 所有新功能时的那台 Mac
And as you saw earlier,
和大家之前看到的一样
we've updated all of our Apple apps
我们把所有的 Apple app 都更新了
and they're running great.
而这些 app 都运行得非常顺畅
Of course, a big part of the Mac experience is third-party apps,
当然 我们在使用 Mac 时 很多时候用的是第三方 app
and we've been working with our friends at Microsoft,
我们一直在和 Microsoft 合作
and they already have Office up and running natively on our new Macs.
Microsoft 的 Office 软件 已经在新 Mac 上顺畅运行了
Let's take a look at Word.
让我们来看一看 Word
It runs great.
运行非常完美
Scrolling is super smooth.
上下滚动非常流畅
Everything you do is just super responsive.
所有操作的响应都是那么流畅
Next let's check out Excel.
接下来 让我们看看 Excel
Just as you'd expect, complex sheets and elements like this map
如你所料 复杂的表格和像这张地图一样的元素
all update instantly.
数据更新都是瞬间完成的
And next let's take a look at PowerPoint.
然后再来看一下 PowerPoint
It's using Metal for rendering, and it performs great.
它用 Metal 来做渲染 效果非常好
For instance, check out how I can see all the layers of my slide in 3D.
例如 大家看看我能在 3D 模式下 看到这页幻灯片的所有图层
The animation is perfectly fluid.
动画效果流畅至极
Now, we've also been working closely with our friends at Adobe
我们还与 Adobe 公司紧密合作
to bring Creative Cloud to our new Macs.
从而让我们的新款 Mac 可以运行 Creative Cloud 创意应用软件
Here's Lightroom running native on Apple Silicon.
这是在 Apple 芯片上 直接运行的 Lightroom
Navigating large libraries of DNG images is super fast,
浏览大型 DNG 图片库时速度超快
and all of Lightroom's editing controls are available right here.
这里 Lightroom 所有的编辑控件 都是可用的
Let's apply an adjustment to this image.
我们来对这张图片做一下调整
Well, that's much better.
这样好看多了
And we can apply that same edit to all of these images in a single step.
我们只需要一步操作 就能批量编辑所有图片
Looks great.
看起来很不错
Next, let me show you the app I know many of you wanna see:
接下来我要展示的这个 app 大家想必都想看看
Photoshop.
那就是 Photoshop
Here is a five-gigabyte Photoshop file by photographer Stephen Wilkes.
这是摄影师 Stephen Wilkes 用 Photoshop 做的文件 大小是 5GB
Now this is a heavy-duty document with lots of layers.
里面包含了很多个图层 处理起来任务量相当繁重
Now let's add one more bird in there.
那么我们在这里再添加一只鸟
Not totally comfortable with the level of social distancing, but let's keep going.
这个程度的社交距离让人不太舒服 不过我们还是继续吧
And let's check out how smooth the animation is as I zoom out.
我们来看看 图片缩放时的动画效果有多么流畅
Wow. Beautiful.
真是太美了
Finally, let's turn to one of our most sophisticated apps:
最后 我们再来看 我们最复杂精妙的 app 之一
Final Cut Pro.
Final Cut Pro
Here it is running on Apple Silicon for the first time.
这是它第一次在 Apple 芯片上运行
Let's play back some 4K video.
我们来放一段 4K 视频
As you can see, playback is super smooth.
可以看到 视频播放非常流畅
And all your filters are here, and you can apply them in real time.
所有的 filter 都在这里 可以实时应用到视频上
Let's try some color correction.
我们来试一下色彩校正
And I can even add animated titles and lens flare...
我还可以添加动画式字幕和镜头眩光
all during live playback.
And Final Cut takes advantage
Final Cut 还可以利用
of the unique capabilities of the Apple Neural Engine
Apple 神经网络引擎的独特功能
with a new feature that analyzes video and intelligently crops it
对视频 进行分析和智能裁剪
to keep the most important action in the frame.
让镜头时刻对准最重要的动作
But that's not all.
但这并非全部
Final Cut fully exploits the system's multicore architecture
Final Cut 能够充分利用 该系统的多核架构
to let us play back not just one or two, but three streams
在一个 A12Z 处理器上可以同时播放 不止一、两个 而是三个视频流
of full-resolution 4K ProRes, all on an A12Z processor.
而且都采用全分辨率的 4K ProRes 格式 全部运行在 A12Z 芯片上
Amazing.
这太惊人了
So that's a first look at Universal apps on Apple Silicon.
现在我们对 Apple 芯片上的 Universal app 有了初步了解
We're really excited to see so much great work on native apps.
我们很高兴看到原生 app 上有这么多 超棒的功能
These apps even get more amazing when they're built to take advantage of
如果利用芯片的 各种强大功能构建这些 app
the Silicon's powerful capabilities.
这些 app 还能变得更加出色
Like its incredible CPU and graphics performance,
例如它出色的 CPU 和图形性能
a unified memory architecture and the Neural Engine
它的统一内存架构和神经网络引擎
which accelerates advanced machine-learning tasks.
能让高级机器学习任务增速
The transition to Apple Silicon is also great for developers
对于已经针对其他 Apple 平台 优化过 app 的开发者而言
who've already optimized their apps for other Apple platforms.
过渡成 Apple 芯片也很有好处
The shared architecture across our products
这个遍及我们产品的共享架构
means that their code will absolutely sing on our new Macs.
代表着他们的代码 绝对能在新款 Mac 上正常运行
And there's even more to the story.
而且还不止于此
We're doing some really important things
我们正在做一些很重要的事
to make this transition seamless for our users.
能让我们的用户实现无缝过渡
Now, while we expect most developers will go native immediately,
虽然我们期待绝大多数开发者 都能马上开始开发原生 app
we wanna make sure that users can run all of their apps on day one,
我们力图确保用户们能够在第一天 就顺利运行所有 app
even if some apps haven't yet been updated.
哪怕其中有些 app 还没有更新
Now, we've been down this road before.
我们之前也经历过这样的事情
When we transitioned from PowerPC to Intel processors,
当初我们从 PowerPC 过渡为 Intel 处理器
a cornerstone of that transition was Rosetta,
过渡中最重要的部分就是 Rosetta
a technology that makes it possible to run PowerPC apps on Intel-based Macs.
这个技术让 PowerPC 的 app 在 基于 Intel 的 Mac 上运行成为可能
macOS Big Sur will include a new version of Rosetta, Rosetta 2.
macOS Big Sur 内包括一个 新版本的 Rosetta 也就是 Rosetta 2
Rosetta 2 automatically translates your existing Mac apps
Rosetta 2 能自动转译现有的 Mac app
so they work on new Macs with Apple Silicon.
让它们得以在采用 Apple 芯片的 新款 Mac 上运行
And this time Rosetta is even faster, more powerful and more compatible.
这次的 Rosetta 比以往更迅捷 更强大 兼容性也更高
It translates the apps when you install them,
它会在 app 安装时对其进行转译
so they can launch immediately and be instantly responsive.
这样它们便可以立刻启动 并且立即作出反应
And Rosetta 2 can also translate code on the fly when needed,
Rosetta 2 还能在有需要的时候 转译运行中的代码
like for web browsers with just-in-time JavaScript compilers or for Java code.
比如对采用准时制 JavaScript 编译器的 浏览器或是 Java 代码进行转译
It even handles the most complex Pro Apps and their plug-ins.
无论多么复杂的专业应用及其插件 它都能够处理
Rosetta 2 is transparent to users, and the performance is amazing.
Rosetta 2 对用户透明 其性能表现也十分出色
We're also introducing new Virtualization technologies in macOS Big Sur.
我们还会把新的虚拟化技术 引入 macOS Big Sur
So, for developers who wanna run other environments like Linux
如果开发者想运行 Linux 等其他环境
or tools like Docker, we have you covered.
或是 Docker 之类的工具 这都没有问题
When you put all of these technologies together,
把所有这些技术聚合到一起
Universal, Rosetta and Virtualization,
Universal、Rosetta、虚拟化技术
you have a system that can run an amazing diversity of apps.
你将会得到一个能够运行 各种各样 app 的系统
To show you how this all comes together, I'll hand it over to Andreas Wendker.
下面请 Andreas Wendker 来讲一讲 如何将这几种技术聚合到一起
Thanks, Craig.
谢了 Craig
Let's take a look at some existing apps running under Rosetta.
Rosetta, of course, works great with all sorts of apps you use every day.
But for our first demo, I'd like to show you something a bit more challenging.
但作为我们的第一个演示版本 我想展示一些更有挑战性的内容
This is Maya, the powerful animation and modeling software
这是 Maya 一款功能强大的动画与建模软件
running great here on Apple Silicon.
在 Apple 芯片上运行良好
I already have a model open that consists of over six million polygons
我这里已经打开了一个模型 它由超过六百万个多边形组成
and, as you can see, I can fluidly move around in this scene.
可以看到 我可以在这个场景里灵活移动
So let's make it more challenging and bring in textures and shaders as well.
我们把 texture 和 shader 也加进去 让它变得更有挑战性一点
And still, everything is incredibly fluid.
一切依然无比流畅
So Rosetta works great, and the performance is simply fantastic.
Rosetta 非常好用 性能表现也非同凡响
But Rosetta isn't just for apps.
但 Rosetta 并非只服务于 app
It also works amazingly well with games.
它在游戏上的效果也非常出色
I can even use a game controller.
我甚至可以用游戏手柄来操作
This is Shadow of the Tomb Raider,
这是《Shadow of the Tomb Raider》
a high-end AAA game that's using our Metal APIs.
一款使用我们 Metal APIs 的 高端 AAA 游戏
I downloaded it directly from the Mac App Store,
我是直接从 Mac App Store 下载的
so it's completely unmodified,
完全没有修改过
and it is absolutely beautiful.
Let me jump into the water.
让我跳入水中
You can see some of the lighting effects here.
这里可以看到一些光照效果
And as I follow the path, you can see the game is responsive,
在我沿着这条路往前走时 大家可以看到这款游戏响应及时
it's smooth,
运行流畅
and the best part is, you're running the 1080p as a translated app
最棒的是 作为一款经过转译的 app 和一款通过模拟器运行的游戏
and an emulation.
它可以在 1080p 下运行
So these new Macs, they are fast.
这些新款 Mac 运行速度真是快
You can see some more of the lighting effects here.
这里可以看到更多的光照效果
It's awesome what Rosetta can do with existing games.
Rosetta 对现有游戏的影响 实在令人感到震撼
Now, as Craig mentioned, many of our users rely on apps from other environments.
正如 Craig 之前所说 很多用户都需要用到其他环境下的 app
So let me bring up a Linux VM in Parallels Desktop.
那么我现在在 Parallel Desktop 里 打开一个 Linux 虚拟机
You can see the graphical user interface designed for Linux here.
这里可以看到针对 Linux 设计的 图形用户界面
But, of course, many developers like to use Linux for hosting servers.
当然 很多开发者喜欢用 Linux 来当主机服务器
So let me dive down to the command line and launch in Apache Web Server.
那么我就通过命令行来实现这一点 开启 Apache Web Server
And now I can simply bring up Safari
现在我可以打开 Safari 浏览器
and browse the website of the server I just launched in the Linux VM.
浏览我刚刚在 Linux 虚拟机里 所启动的服务器的网站
Here it is.
就是这个
Now I want to show you one more type of app to run on these new Macs
我想再给大家看一种可以 在新款 Mac 上运行的 app
that we haven't even told you about yet,
我们还没有跟大家谈到过它
and that is iPhone and iPad apps.
那就是 iPhone 和 iPad 上的 app
Since they've been built to run on the same Apple Silicon
鉴于它们基于同款 Apple 芯片构建
that we're using on our new Macs,
与新款 Mac 的芯片一样
they will run natively, completely unmodified,
它们也可以完全不经修改
on the new Macs as well.
就在新款 Mac 上运行
Let me show you a few.
下面我就来展示几款这样的 app
This here is one of my favorite games, Monument Valley 2.
这是我很喜欢的一款游戏 《纪念碑谷 2》
It's fun to play here on the new Mac.
在新款 Mac 上玩起来很有意思
And if I want to catch up on my guitar lessons, I can use Fender Play.
[guitar plays]
Or if I want to relax at the end of the day a little bit,
或者劳累了一天之后 我想稍微放松一下
I can bring up the Calm app.
那么我可以打开 Calm
And that was just a quick look at Rosetta, Virtualization
至此 我向大家简单介绍了 Rosetta、虚拟化
and support for iPhone and iPad apps, giving users amazing versatility
以及对 iPhone 和 iPad app 的支持 给予用户无与伦比的多功能性
for running apps and other environments with macOS on Apple Silicon.
还有通过在Apple 芯片上运行的 macOS 来运行各种 app 和其他环境
Back to you, Craig.
Craig 把时间交还给你
Thanks, Andreas.
谢谢你 Andreas
As you saw,
如你所见
Macs built with Apple Silicon will be able to run iPhone and iPad apps directly.
采用 Apple 芯片的 Mac 能直接运行 iPhone 和 iPad app
Starting day one, users can download these apps right from the Mac App Store,
从第一天开始 用户便可以 从 Mac App Store 下载这些 app
and most apps will just work with no changes from the developer.
大多数 app 无需开发者对其进行改动 便可以直接运行
With everything we're doing,
在我们的努力之下
the range of apps that users will be able to run on these new Macs
用户在新款 Mac 上所能使用的 app 覆盖范围之广
is truly unprecedented.
堪称前所未有
Together, we have all the technologies in place to make this an amazing transition.
我们把所有这些技术汇聚起来 完成这个令人惊喜的转换
The vast majority of Mac apps
绝大多数的 Mac app
can be recompiled as Universal in a few days,
只需短短几天 就可以被重新编译成 Universal app
so users can have fast, native apps.
好让用户能够享受到速度超快的原生 app
Rosetta 2 runs existing Mac apps,
通过 Rosetta 2 来运行现有的 Mac app
our Virtualization technology makes it easier than ever
有了我们的虚拟化技术 把如 Linux 这样的其他环境
to bring other environments, like Linux, to the Mac,
放到 Mac 运行上变得前所未有的简单
and Mac users can, for the first time, run iOS and iPadOS apps directly,
Mac 用户有史以来第一次可以 直接运行 iOS 和 iPadOS app
tapping into the world's most vital app ecosystem.
进入到全世界最生机勃勃的 app 生态系统
Now, we know our Mac developers will be eager to get started on this new platform.
我知道我们的 Mac 开发者 迫切想在这个新平台上开始工作
So to get them going right away, we're launching a Quick Start Program.
为了让他们立刻开始 我们将开展一个 Quick Start 计划
The focus of the Quick Start Program
这个 Quick Start 计划的重点
is to enable developers to make their apps Universal
是让开发者把他们的 app 变成 Universal
and take advantage of all the capabilities of Apple Silicon.
并充分利用 Apple 芯片的所有功能
Developers will have access to documentation and sample code,
开发者们将可以 从 developer.apple.com 的论坛上
forums on developer.apple.com,
获得说明文档和示例代码
priority DTS support incidents, and access to labs around the world.
优先开发者技术支持 (DTS) 事件 并能接触世界各地的实验室
This program also includes new Developer Transition Kit hardware
该计划还包括新的 Developer Transition Kit (DTK) 硬件
so developers can get going even before we ship production systems.
这样在我们的量产系统面市之前 各位开发者就可以着手开始自己的工作了
The DTK hardware takes the form of a Mac mini,
DTK 硬件采用了 Mac mini 的外型
but one with an A12Z SoC inside.
不过里面装的是一颗 A12Z 系统芯片
It has desktop specs, including 16 gigabytes of memory,
它拥有台式机的规格 包括 16G 内存
a 512-gig SSD, and a complement of Mac I/O ports.
一块 512G 的 固态硬盘 以及附带的 Mac I/O 端口
Most significantly, it will include
最重要的是 它还包括
the macOS Big Sur developer beta and Xcode tools.
macOS Big Sur 开发者 beta 版 和 Xcode 工具
Developers will be able to apply to the program
各位开发者今天即可申请参加这项计划
at developer.apple.com today.
就在 developer.apple.com
We will be shipping units out starting this week
我们本周将开始发货
so you can get to work.
这样你们就可以着手工作了
So that's how macOS Big Sur is paving the way
macOS Big Sur 就是这样铺平道路
for a smooth transition to Apple Silicon.
让大家可以顺利过渡到 Apple 芯片
This year, we're elevating the Mac to a whole new level.
今年 我们将把 Mac 带到 前所未有的新高度
And it's an incredible opportunity for developers.
这对开发者来说是不可思议的机会
I can't wait to see what you all create,
我迫不及待地想要欣赏 你们创造出来的作品
and I can't wait until we can all be together in person again.
也迫不及待地想要与你们再次亲身相聚
And now, back to Tim.
下面，回到 Tim
Thank you, Craig, and thank you, Johny.
谢谢 Craig 谢谢 Johny
It truly is a historic day for the Mac.
对于 Mac 而言 这绝对是具有历史意义的一天
Our vision for the Mac has always been about
一直以来 我们对 Mac 的愿景都是
embracing breakthrough innovation and having the courage
拥抱突破性创新
to make bold changes.
勇于做出大胆改变
Every time we've done this, the Mac has come out stronger and more capable.
每当我们做到这一点 Mac 就会变得更强、更有能力
And I have never been more confident
今天 我对于 Mac 的未来
about the future of the Mac than I am today.
怀有前所未有的坚定信心
So, what's the timeline for this transition?
那么这个过渡的时间表是怎样的呢？
Well, for developers,
对于开发者群体
it begins this week with the valuable information
从这周开始 我们会在本届大会上
delivered at this conference as well as applying for the Quick Start Program.
向各位传达有价值的信息 同时开启 Quick Start 计划的申请程序
And for the customers,
而对于消费者群体
we expect to ship our first Mac with Apple Silicon by the end of this year,
第一款采用 Apple 芯片的 Mac 预期将在今年年底面市
and we expect the transition to take about two years.
我们预计这个过渡会花费大约两年时间
We plan to continue to support and release new versions of macOS
我们计划在未来几年里继续支持并发布 macOS 的新版
for Intel-based Macs for years to come.
用来支持基于 Intel 芯片的 Mac
In fact, we have some new Intel-based Macs in the pipeline
实际上 我们正在酝酿一些新的 基于 Intel 芯片的 Mac
that we're really excited about.
我们对此十分期待
What a huge leap forward for the Mac and for Apple.
对于 Mac 和 Apple 而言 这真是一次巨大的飞跃
Apple Silicon will bring amazing technologies,
Apple 芯片将带来杰出的技术
industry-leading performance,
业界领先的性能表现
and a common architecture across all of our products.
以及触达我们全线产品的通用架构
What an incredible day of announcements.
今天的发布会满是惊喜
As you've seen, we haven't stopped innovating.
如你所见 我们从未停止过创新的脚步
We pushed all of our platforms forward in some amazing new ways.
我们通过一些全新的方式 推动所有平台向前发展
Our OS releases will be available as developer betas today.
今天我们要发布的 OS 将作为开发者 beta 版上线
And each of them will have a public beta, including watchOS for the very first time,
而且每个 OS 都将有一个公开 beta 版 包括首次采取这种做法的 watchOS
starting next month.
自下个月开始推出
And all of this great software will be available to our customers this fall.
今年秋天 各位消费者即可 用上这些出色的软件
We hope you've enjoyed this very special keynote
希望大家喜欢这场特别的 Keynote 主题演讲
and that you're ready for the big week ahead,
也希望大家已经做好准备 迎接未来精彩纷呈的一周
with over 100 engineering-led video sessions,
100 多场工程设计讲座
one-on-one consultations with Apple engineers,
和 Apple 工程师的一对一咨询
and so much more.
和其他多项可参与的内容
We can't wait to start working with all of you
我们迫不及待地想要 与你们所有人开展合作
and watch you do the best work of your lives.
亲眼看着你们打造出 你们人生中最满意的杰作
At Apple, we've always drawn strength
在 Apple 我们的力量一直来源于
from the diversity of our global community
全球群体的多样性
because we truly believe when we all work together,
因为我们真心相信 只要我们团结协作
we can change the world for the better.
就一定能让世界变得更加美好
Thanks to you all for joining us.
感谢各位观看本次演讲
This has been such a big day,
今天的信息量已经如此之大
and it's only the beginning of a huge week to come.
而这才只是刚刚开始 后面还有整整一周等待着我们
So let's have a great WWDC.
请尽情享受这届 WWDC 全球开发者大会吧
["Daydreamer" by Aurora playing]
[song fades]